Krish NAik: There is a lot of my background, just with you.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, I think, if there's any issue in joining the session, you guys can let me in the chat. I think the chats are open, you guys can type.
Krish NAik: And in Q&A, who's this anonymous attendee is asking about the project?
Krish NAik: Yes, what's the issue? Because again, I shared the link. Is that link working that I have shared?
Krish NAik: Quickly, let me know, guys, then… because I feel the link already, I have shared it. Yeah, good morning.
Krish NAik: We do not see the link in the portal. It's really strange, like, I knew that the link is there, but if you ask me, just wait.
Krish NAik: No, no, because let me start sharing my screen.
Krish NAik: This is Richman doesn't text for UI can go through it.
Krish NAik: Fine, let me check the link.
Krish NAik: Because when I, looked here into your dashboard.
Krish NAik: Okay, and when I go to the workshop section, I can see the RAC project tool for RAC.
Krish NAik: Like, why you guys cannot see? It can be an issue from TagMango, because… They are our service provider.
Krish NAik: No, no, no.
Krish NAik: You are in the wrong place. Mometaguf.
Krish NAik: You can link the session. This is not the industry.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: Could you please, share in chat, Sayad Nu?
Krish NAik: We can get the link from the email, alright? Email is fine, I think, yesterday also. But when I look actually here, that's why I feel that the link is here.
Krish NAik: That's why I copy-pasted the link in the forum, so I think you guys can enjoy it.
Krish NAik: I joined from the mail, alright.
Krish NAik: That's why I feel somehow the participants are a bit low today.
Krish NAik: V.
Krish NAik: Nothing that I can do from my side, because I already… and the link that I've shared in the forum, please have it checked that it's working or not.
Krish NAik: Because I feel it should work, it's basically the customer's link only, that had bought it.
Krish NAik: I think no more chats.
Krish NAik: are there, so I think probably every one of you can join it now.
Krish NAik: Hmm, I joined from the chat as well. Thanks, Emma.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: So let's start, I think,
Krish NAik: First of all, okay, take a get pull. I have added the workflows, okay, and then, a little bit, if you remember, in the last class, in the image captioning part.
Krish NAik: There were some issues. Actually, it was a bug, though I was doing the captioning, but actually, I was not embedding it, okay?
Krish NAik: So, because of that, the main problem was that I have already fixed the bug. Everybody, please take a Git pull.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Git pull, like, I already have cherry-picked in the master branch also, but I was working in the deployment branch, so please take a git pull, everybody. Then I think these workflows also, you will get it. I have added it in the master branch and not in the deployment branch.
Krish NAik: I take a get pull of both. Just use the command get pull origin master, okay, and the other one, like, get pull origin deployment. Both the commands just executed.
Krish NAik: today, I want you guys, because I think that everyone can set up Lightning AI ASAP, like, within…
Krish NAik: 5 minutes once the studio is live.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Everybody?
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because going forward, I think I'll be sticking to, like… I paused my studio yesterday, so it should be good. Yeah, yeah, it should be good, don't worry.
Krish NAik: Just remember, whenever you are starting a studio, it will be in CP. Okay, by default, that's actually good, I feel that, always directly getting into. What you can do, you can make a one-switch click.
Krish NAik: So, if I open mine one.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if I… I think everybody can see the screen, okay? So, for example, let me just switch it off right now, okay, and I will show that.
Krish NAik: Because by default, it will be in the CPU mode, you guys have to do a one-click switch to a GPU. So there, again, you can select a GPU according to your own needs.
Krish NAik: Rajivar Kumar Mahara is asking, what is the project name? It is not in the la- it is not in library.
Krish NAik: Which library are you talking about?
Krish NAik: I don't know, like, really, like, many people might have opted.
Krish NAik: No, I think, you are in the wrong place. So, if you're not part of this particular batch, this is not industry-ready project session, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay? It's a different session, so it's nothing.
Krish NAik: We have been already dealing, I think, more than 4 to 5 months with the course, it's not part, so people who are part of that one, they can leave it.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: So, guys, see, right now, my, studio isn't switched on, okay? So, what I will do, I will just click it on, okay? And you will see that by default, it will be on the CPU mode.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from the CPU mode, you need to make a switch.
Krish NAik: And then, rest of the work that you have done, nothing will be lost. Exactly the same thing will be coming in
Krish NAik: I can say, the GPU instance also. Okay, so right now, if you look into, so this is my CPU instance. So right now, I will be going here. Okay, and you can see, switch to GPU, everybody, whoever has switched off yesterday.
Krish NAik: Okay, can you see the switch too? It should be active. so should we activate the lightning again? Yes, activated. Activate it. Everybody.
Krish NAik: Because, the recent changes that I have done, today I want you guys at least to do a thorough testing
Krish NAik: Of the system, at least with the backends that we have tested yesterday.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's it, please switch on.
Krish NAik: Take a git pull, and then we'll be talking about the architectures, all the workflows I have added it in the master branch, I have not added it in the deployment branch. So, take a pull for both of the branches.
Krish NAik: Vautam is asking, is this the continuation of yesterday's session? Yes, Vautam, exactly. It is the continuation of yesterday's session. Okay, so what I will do, I will just click on switch to GPU.
Krish NAik: Okay, and from here, again, like, let's go with L4.
Krish NAik: If you really look into the pricing, always look into the pricing, that… if you remember, yesterday, I used a GPU-based instance.
Krish NAik: So, like, I feel that, T4 having 16 gigs, of VRAM, and it's charging me close to 0.43 credits, okay, whereas L4 is having 24GB of RAM.
Krish NAik: Okay, the VRAM, actually, not your RAM. Okay, so the VRAM is higher. So I feel that this pricing is much better, so I will go with an L4 one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me request, it will take, I think, how many? The wait time is 2 minutes, so we have to wait for 2 minutes, nothing that we can do.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me click on Request.
Krish NAik: So, as you can see, ready, and I have switched on auto-switch machine, so just click on this option, so whenever the machine will be ready, automatically you will be switched to CPU to GPU.
Krish NAik: So, pretty much handy as a developer IP, these options. Whereas in cloud, again, I have to kill the instance, launch a new instance, these things really can be done.
Krish NAik: Yes, one can be leveraged. Yes, yes, yes, yesterday's entire work can be leveraged. That's why I told you just switch off the machine, rather than deleting, because you won't be getting charged.
Krish NAik: We need to do SSH, yes, you can do SSH, there is no problem with the SSH part.
Krish NAik: Once the GPU machine is ready, then only do the SSH. Otherwise, again, your SSH connection will be closed, as the instance will be different from CPU 2G.
Krish NAik: Okay, so when the GPU machine is ready, then only make a switch. So you can see, as I have selected the auto switch, it didn't ask. Otherwise, a pop-up will come, and you have to click on switch.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why always I keep this option.
Krish NAik: Alright, now I'm good to go, with an SSH. Okay, I think it is taking time, 85%, the setup is done.
Krish NAik: Okay, so 86%, one is 100%, then I will be doing the SSH.
Krish NAik: So… where is my item? Just wait.
Krish NAik: Bitbucks?
Krish NAik: at least in my courses in future, i.e, I will be working with Lightning Air, because I feel that if I'm working with AWS and others, this is much more developer-friendly. At least for your personnel R&D, I will suggest everyone, like.
Krish NAik: Till now. I have used Modal also. Modal is also good, but the options are lesser.
Krish NAik: Okay, anybody has used modal here?
Krish NAik: Raul is asking, have you pushed for deployment, perhaps? Both I have pushed, actually.
Krish NAik: Actually, I did the pushing in the deployment branch, but actually, I felt that I updated the caption, bug. Okay, there was a small bug that I cherry-picked into master, so that's why I'm asking you, take a pull-up booth.
Krish NAik: Can you please, yes, it's yes, that is link only, but again, I'll be sharing the link, don't worry. Okay, so, just wait.
Krish NAik: Mmm…
Krish NAik: Okay, so whoever is there new in the session, for them in the chat, I am sharing.
Krish NAik: Gotham is asking, they said end-to-end medical chat, but no, this is nothing that… I think you are in the wrong place.
Krish NAik: Actually, what happens, a lot of students get that, I think, the entire subscription.
Krish NAik: And they do a lot of hopping here and there.
Krish NAik: So I think, right now, the number of participants are fine. I feel that few people have joined late. But, the first thing, the instance setup is ready. Quickly, I'll be taking an SSH.
Krish NAik: Always check the mail, Jatinar, because sometimes if it's an issue, then directly ask it in the forum, because before the class, I always look into the chats, at least.
Krish NAik: Okay, always drop some message, then it becomes clearer, because even I don't know, and really, the service provider is TagMango, and really, like, I'm not really happy with their work or the development. It's really, really slow, okay?
Krish NAik: Okay, so connect via SSH,
Krish NAik: I don't know, it can be a back-end issue, like, today the team will also be off, so tomorrow I will ask the operations team to get connected with TACMAN and let them know the issue.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me just make an SSH connection right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so CD, multimodal RAD. Okay, and right now I'm in the deployment branch, so if I do a git pull, origin, deployment.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the branch.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you can see pretty much, like, I have already done the Git pull.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you guys should also do the same.
Krish NAik: This is everyone, like, this session is not for, projects. This is totally different.
Krish NAik: Gautam. You are on the wrong place. That Class K happens, at night.
Krish NAik: 8pm.
Krish NAik: All right, so now, the first thing, if you remember yesterday's work that I have done, so… people who have joined today, you can actually, like, switch your branch, and you can have a look into the LightningEi deploy.md file, the setup is there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first of all, as I have pulled it new, I will just look into whether I have the access to the OCR or not. Okay, so let me just make a split-screen view, so that it becomes easier for everyone.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now you can see that Olama is not running.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me just make docker compose up. The first command will actually do the setup of Olama.
Krish NAik: So, always remember, whenever you are switching, at least you have to do this bare minimum task, okay, that the execution of Pulama, because these things will be pretty much deleted every time from the memory, because a new instance will be allocated.
Krish NAik: In that way, they are actually saying, can you send the deployment of Raj? Yes.
Krish NAik: Stay in the deployment.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just wait, like, once I have done it, then I'll be doing the setup.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if you really look into yesterday, whatever the ports that you have created, it will be also automatically attached with the machine.
Krish NAik: Okay, so most of the things alar, so just these Docker things and others, they won't be there.
Krish NAik: In brief.
Krish NAik: Alright, now I feel that. Let me get the… Okay, so… the OCR?
Krish NAik: model.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this generally takes around, like, 10 to 15 seconds you really need to wait. As you can see, this is in the starting phase right now, so it takes around 10 seconds, roughly.
Krish NAik: That, I picked.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes Ulama List.
Krish NAik: Alright, I can see the OCR model is up.
Krish NAik: Okay, and let's finally make the build.
Krish NAik: And most of the times, you can actually create a simple, like, the commands I have executed separately, just keep a bash script with you. Then run the script, everything will be out.
Krish NAik: Is there anybody who has not taken yesterday's class?
Krish NAik: About setting up the project?
Krish NAik: Okay, only Jatinder. Jatinder, what you can do? Already, I've shared the, Git link.
Krish NAik: I missed the last one hour, I was not feeling well. Alright, I think in the last one hour only, we did the Lightning setup, so just switch on to your Lightning accounts, launch a studio. Okay, when you are launching, select a GPU instance, at least having T4 or an L4. Once you have that, then,
Krish NAik: the report that I have shared, switched to the
Krish NAik: deployment branch from master, okay, and you will be having a markdown file. So, in that Lightning AI deploy, so you just need to execute these three commands.
Krish NAik: Because that's the only thing, just focused about the local things, but I feel that this setup, anybody can do it very quickly. So, maximum, like, 10 minutes.
Krish NAik: Alright, so my quadrant is starting up.
Krish NAik: Okay, now the application will, because it's a cold start, because in the cold start, from my CPU, I'll be offloading the models of PP detection layout.
Krish NAik: and the, OCR, the GLM OCR model into the VRAM, okay? So that's why that, the offloading is taking place. It takes roughly around 1 minute, okay, 1 minute to 2 minutes.
Krish NAik: When I see in the logs that the UVGON application is ready, then actually I will try to open it, and I will try to access the public UR.
Krish NAik: No, no, today we are not doing the ACL sub-band.
Krish NAik: Today, I've added, like,
Krish NAik: I have added that captioning fix, so I want you guys to do the testing. Because I made the fix, actually, I didn't get the time to do a lot of…
Krish NAik: Martha is asking, are you doing the offloading manually? Yes, I have kept it in the script, in the startup.
Krish NAik: before the applications startup, it should be offloaded. Otherwise, what will happen with us? So, the first request will come, then the offloading. So, generally, in the first request, the response time will be very, very high.
Krish NAik: It can be, like, you can think about, by default, it takes around 180 seconds, okay, in GPUs. Now, on top of that, add 3 to 4 minutes more.
Krish NAik: Because of offloading. So the first required actually takes a lot of time.
Krish NAik: I hope you get that, Motodana.
Krish NAik: why I'm doing the uploading before the application, before the first hit anybody makes.
Krish NAik: to the core application.
Krish NAik: KB Kache is not part of this chatandar, so that's why, really, I won't be talking about KDACHA here.
Krish NAik: Because to tell about KP Catch A, first I have to talk about what is the issue with MHA.
Krish NAik: Okay, in, multi-8, because at every point, you won't be calculating so good. Those things, I'll be keeping it separately.
Krish NAik: Alright, so in the logs, you can see Mubicon running at this particular port, so let me try to open that port, so let me just click here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just check, with quadrant.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I can see, yes, Quadrant is up. Let me open the dashboard of Quadrant.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… yesterday, I think,
Krish NAik: Okay, so… alright, no collections will be there for sure.
Krish NAik: Now, let me open the Fast API.
Krish NAik: All right, got it.
Krish NAik: From here slash talk.
Krish NAik: Eiso…
Krish NAik: Let me make an ingest, okay? And, this time, let me just pass the attention is all you need paper.
Krish NAik: Maybe Kajal's really an… The most important concept, if you are actually doing inference engineering.
Krish NAik: In Netherlands.
Krish NAik: So, really,
Krish NAik: That's why, even with respect to daily catch-up, I'll be showing you, because right now, even I am working on much more, deeper on that one.
Krish NAik: Children.
Krish NAik: First of all, let's do, because I feel that at least 80% of the advanced batch curriculum I have already created, so a little bit of inputs I'll be taking from you guys also.
Krish NAik: Fine, let me just take a PDF file, and this time I'll be taking a bigger PDF file. So, attention paper, let's go ahead with that.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, I feel that this is a bigger one.
Krish NAik: Okay, or do you want me to take a bigger one? Please let me know. Should I go with a bigger PDF? Then I'll be taking the Transformers Catalog PDF. Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Everybody, should I go with a bigger PDF, like 60-70 pages?
Krish NAik: Yeah, with more images. Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Yeah, let me open.
Krish NAik: Transformer… okay, already dates there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is really a very long one, having 60-70 pages. Let's try to see what happens here.
Krish NAik: CV papers also, I can take it. This one was also having a lot of images.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's start, at least, let's see.
Krish NAik: That, everything is working fine or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, in the meantime, what I will do, I will open another instance, actually.
Krish NAik: Because I need to keep a track of the VRAM usage also.
Krish NAik: Soon…
Krish NAik: SSH…
Krish NAik: That is SSH, I think. This is the one.
Krish NAik: Alright, you can see, like, this has came close to 16GB, so 16GB when it is there, that's why I don't prefer working with T4, you know, the limits in T4 is 16GB of VRAM, but here, it really… so…
Krish NAik: sometimes in T4, like, you might get an error of a out-of-memory issue.
Krish NAik: But here I can see that, yes, the amount of VRAM which is getting used is really high.
Krish NAik: No, singing papers are fine, and you will book it.
Krish NAik: Actually, the one that I have used here, here also you can actually
Krish NAik: The catalog paper, a lot of images are there.
Krish NAik: Actually, much more complex with, multiple architectures.
Krish NAik: I show you. Anybody has gone through the paper of Transformers Catalog?
Krish NAik: Yes? Anybody has read the paper?
Krish NAik: So, like, in this one, also, you have images in there.
Krish NAik: But lesser one, you'll see the, like, object detection papers, I'll be getting more.
Krish NAik: Sarah is asking, I want to give one PDF if you help, extract text from it.
Krish NAik: Mount rate, you mentioned.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine, it's having text and images, I'm not worried about that.
Krish NAik: How should I give you? Just share me a Google Drive link or something like that.
Krish NAik: re-transfer link. Anything, just… shit.
Krish NAik: How many is we are there to share. Now, this is a bigger PDF, so for sure, the inference time will be much higher. By default, like, I think yesterday we worked with the Doppling technical report, and there we were having how much? Like, around 180 seconds it took around.
Krish NAik: It was having, I think, 8 or 9 pages, but this time daily, I've increased it 10M, so the inference time is much higher this time.
Krish NAik: Just have a check in the chats, I'm not sure that, if you can do it, it's great.
Krish NAik: Thoro.
Krish NAik: Everybody, like, yesterday's testing, just try to ingest, and basically, if you remember, the main problem was with respect to tables.
Krish NAik: Okay. So, like, changing the LLM is one solution, but I feel that we should not be only dependent on changing the LLMs, rather than on the core structure. So, you guys, please do the testing with the technical report, and try to ask questions around the table that you have.
Krish NAik: At least the M3 Max and the Intel Zone, that particular TV. You should be getting.
Krish NAik: Mitesh is asking, is it possible that OpenAI through Azure OpenAI will not work in Lightning?
Krish NAik: Due to regional restriction.
Krish NAik: multiplayer.
Krish NAik: I'm not sure about that, Mitesh, because, here…
Krish NAik: Really, when you are launching an instance, the… That part.
Krish NAik: India region instances, I don't feel separately they have it.
Krish NAik: Here, because directly they say instances.
Krish NAik: You are getting that the key is invalid, but local is human.
Krish NAik: Ideally, for that, what can be the solution, I'm thinking.
Krish NAik: If it is very specific for a region, then…
Krish NAik: top size 6MB to 10MB. Can you get the lighting, AI CPU, and memory utilization?
Krish NAik: EI CPU, AI, like, you can do it on CPUs, but the CPU inference time will be very, very high. That's the only thing, no. Like, at least I can say that in CPU inferencing, it might take 6 minutes
Krish NAik: Okay, like, 5 to 6 minutes, at least on GPUs, I know that it will be roughly around, like, 3 minutes, like, 50% downtime, at least with an L4. If I go with better GPUs, like L4TS, A100s.
Krish NAik: Okay, then at least I'll be getting better speeds there.
Krish NAik: Chair and Teja is, telling, jumping done, please have it checked, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Let's see, because… Let me just check the quadrant, first of all.
Krish NAik: The ingestion is done.
Krish NAik: Okay, so approximately 120 points, are there, fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's try to,
Krish NAik: Take some questions from images, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Let me first of all have a look, at least in the image part.
Krish NAik: Let me see that, below is respectable.
Krish NAik: Oops.
Krish NAik: because I'm doing a live testing, I'm not really sure that, whether it will, but I will try to
Krish NAik: Pass, something… Integrated.
Krish NAik: Filter modality, let's remove it, let's go with 5, I think 5 is… The neat.
Krish NAik: Explain me the Transformers, timeline from…
Krish NAik: How the hell query transformers okay?
Krish NAik: Reading from where I got this one.
Krish NAik: Okay… I was typing G Suite.
Krish NAik: Explain me the Transformers timeline, from figure 6.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: Okay, I am asking directly based on a figure, let me see that whether it can pick up or not, because this is directly figure sales transformers timeline. Okay, so let's try to have a look whether it can respond or not.
Krish NAik: Mmm, maybe rank, let me try.
Krish NAik: Alright, now I can see that, the correct modality, because the timeline, I feel that this particular keyword is there a lot.
Krish NAik: Okay, now let me try to, get directly, figure safe exactly what are the chunks that are coming.
Krish NAik: Because something in between I need.
Krish NAik: To get the information about figure sets.
Krish NAik: Figure 6, the first modality that is coming. I can see this chronological timeline, and this is from page 14, and the chunk number is still 4 that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so page 14, let me just have a look exactly, like, what is the content there.
Krish NAik: then only I can say.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is, okay, the chronological timeline.
Krish NAik: Okay, I feel that, at least in the document, it has picked the correct one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me try to pass,
Krish NAik: Because I'm right now doing a…
Krish NAik: Full testing, so here, I feel that this information which is coming, this is fine.
Krish NAik: Mmm… Please refer to the previous image.
Krish NAik: Right now, if I look into the… Off… Alright.
Krish NAik: The previous image, let me look into the previous image once.
Krish NAik: This is Figure 5.
Krish NAik: Alright, you are asking, explain me the Transformers family tree, let me see this.
Krish NAik: I have not actually, changed the LLM, I have kept GPT-4 out, okay? I'm…
Krish NAik: That is the other thing around.
Krish NAik: But, just look into the performance of the read anchor, because the entire thing is there.
Krish NAik: Now, when I said explained me, just wait.
Krish NAik: Let me check with this one. Because this is a much more generic question, which I feel, okay, because my focus is on the image modality much more, because I know that if I pass something like this.
Krish NAik: it will work. There won't be any type of issues, because this is text-based so much.
Krish NAik: Okay, and right now, when I actually go, I can see the first modality which has been picked up. This is from page 14. So I can say that, yes, and right now, if you really look into, based on the answer, the transformers family tree is depicted as in
Krish NAik: Figure 5 on page 14.
Krish NAik: Figure 5, okay, now this is page number 14. I can see that, okay, now this is coming correct, but if I actually go ahead with the next one.
Krish NAik: Okay, because you have to analyze the answers, like, where it is working and where.
Krish NAik: You just search for Transformers Catalog Papers Home, okay, in Google, you will get it.
Krish NAik: Okay, here I have two images, the Transformers timeline based on this one.
Krish NAik: This is the family tree. Family tree is coming correct, but, the transformer's, timeline. Let me just, change a little bit, like, explain me Transformers, pipeline, okay? And let me… because I feel that this answer is correct, and this is actually the image modality which has been picked up.
Krish NAik: Please do link into your actual retrieval results, because in your retrieval, the preference should be coming to image, rather than text.
Krish NAik: Because from here, I can see that, okay, so explain to me the transformers…
Krish NAik: What was the key word? Timeline.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, timeline… Okay, let me pass the keyword timeline.
Krish NAik: Ingrid.
Krish NAik: Explain me the… alright?
Krish NAik: Based on the answer which is coming, I can see here, Figure 7. Figure 7 is in…
Krish NAik: Which page? Page number 15, okay? Because I feel that it's page number 15, and here it's telling. Because this is a structure layer, so I always know what is the page number exactly it's there. And the modality is coming as image, okay? Fine. So this is also working.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, Chalan is asking, okay, Sharon is saying, try this one. Transformers Typeline Explain Figure Sets.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me just pass that one. Because little bit of query transformation, if I feel that on top of this, if I add
Krish NAik: things will be better, because I have, this is pretty much the vanilla query that I'm directly passing. No query, various transformations.
Krish NAik: Let me see that, what results I am getting. Okay, so this one is not working for me, because it will be different, you have to understand. When you make an API call.
Krish NAik: In your case, the content which is getting generated, the image text, it will be different. For me, it will be different. Because that is the response from the LLM. We cannot standardize it for everyone.
Krish NAik: We just can standardize the structure, but actually, within that structure, what will be the text that cannot be standardized? I hope everybody gets that. Yes or no, please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Because that part is not in our hand, actually.
Krish NAik: only we can say that, follow this particular structure only. That's why, because that's not deterministic systems.
Krish NAik: So, the result will be deterministic, but I can see that, yes, it's working, but mmm.
Krish NAik: Because in figures, it's actually, like, why this figures… Sex as creating more issues.
Krish NAik: Because Figure 6 is their brother's described Transformers family.
Krish NAik: Any other thing that I can pass?
Krish NAik: This is based on the… okay, so let me just try to pick up something others.
Krish NAik: The family tree was working, we already done the testing, if anything else is there.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Something from this image, I feel that, the scale.production… Beautiful.
Krish NAik: If I directly pass a Figure 2-based question, let me see what happens.
Krish NAik: Figure 2 on the page illustrates the attention mechanism from Sony, and it includes two parts, the scale.product, and I can see that, yes, this is coming correct.
Krish NAik: Okay, so initially, the modality will be text, that is based on that. Alright, text modalities, text modalities.
Krish NAik: And I can see that,
Krish NAik: This is a different one.
Krish NAik: Okay… Explanation about that.
Krish NAik: This is coming fine.
Krish NAik: Now, let's try to go ahead with,
Krish NAik: Because here, I can see directly, if I pass figure 2,
Krish NAik: The answer that I'm getting, it's exactly the correct one. In page number 7… okay.
Krish NAik: And page number 71IC.
Krish NAik: This is actually page number 7 only, yes.
Krish NAik: So I can say the chunking strategy.
Krish NAik: Definitely.
Krish NAik: All right, now, okay, Podale, sir, you have passed both, okay? Alright, in your case, it works. Really, in my case, it's not necessary, that's fine.
Krish NAik: Always remember that, because this is a little bit determinal, non-deterministic, okay? Explain me the timeline based on Figure 6 and Figure 7. Okay, let's see that, whether this works or not.
Krish NAik: So that's why I want you guys to do a thorough testing and really understand that where it's failing much more.
Krish NAik: Alright, so Figure 6 presents a chronological timeline, okay, all right, this is… and the information is actually coming from the text. I feel that, this is that, figure-based information.
Krish NAik: Alright, and here, the caption data of that particular figure, okay, it worked in that way.
Krish NAik: Alright, I can see that it's working.
Krish NAik: a little bit of query transformations that I really need to…
Krish NAik: I feel that… which can be added. Now, let me just ask on this one, explain me the transformer's pipeline based on Figure 6, whether this works or not.
Krish NAik: Now, this is not working, only because of the keyword Maybe.
Krish NAik: I can actually,
Krish NAik: pass it through Heidi, okay, and I can make it better, because you guys already know a lot of other things are there which can be integrated, but we are doing nothing, because it's a plain query that I am passing.
Krish NAik: Alright, Motada, you are asking, okay, which are recently published LLMs? Okay, let me take this one, and let me…
Krish NAik: Pass document.
Krish NAik: Because I can say that it's working, the little bit we need to work on various transformations.
Krish NAik: recently published LLMs from March 2023 to include LAMA, FLAN into 2. Okay, according to the papers, I can say that this is based on page number 16. All right, the information is coming from the diagram captions.
Krish NAik: So, yes, I can say.
Krish NAik: somehow, better than yesterday, but in this paper, really, tables are missing, so let me just go to page 16.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Try to ask a question from Figure 3 also, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay? The figure 3 in page number 9 that you have.
Krish NAik: Let me look into page 40. So, everybody, please do a thorough testing according to you. That's why I'm giving you time, and look into the cons, because the next step, probably next week, I will be working on those particular cons, or you guys at least start doing the work. Okay.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that I can attach ID and query transformational, but that will be my last and last result. But before that, what we can do, actually, because I feel that that will be my last step, but before that, anything that can be done on me.
Krish NAik: Alright, recently published. More information can be there, but yes, lesser somehow IP. The catalog list, and now the entire catalog list is there.
Krish NAik: Hari, Gina re-ranker, credits are exhausted very fast.
Krish NAik: they give 10 million tokens. I feel that it's really high.
Krish NAik: Okay, what you can do, you can reduce the total number of chunks that you are passing. In my case, I was passing 20, reduce that number to 10.
Krish NAik: Okay, Hadi.
Krish NAik: I feel that that is the other way workaround that can be done.
Krish NAik: Avid, which link you were looking for.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, this paper is a totally different one that I picked up for today's testing.
Krish NAik: But I feel that, okay, because, yes, things are working, but with respect to query, I feel that query transformations will, if I try to add it.
Krish NAik: Because Heidi, it's not really so much time-taking operation, but, I can do that.
Krish NAik: So, you guys, let me know, right, where you can.
Krish NAik: This paper link you are asking, It's been preliminary.
Krish NAik: Anybody who has learned Transformers, everybody knows about these people.
Krish NAik: The fuck you guys.
Krish NAik: new.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, simply search, always search. I told you, Transformers Catalog paper, if you write it, you will get it.
Krish NAik: All right, because I feel that it's performing better, but at least I need to test with some tables, so let me fetch, somewhere. I think, the Nemote 1Pass paper, it was having…
Krish NAik: tables, okay? So let me just open that.
Krish NAik: Emotron parch paper.
Krish NAik: Because now I want to do a little bit of testing on, tables.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here I have one table.
Krish NAik: I feel,
Krish NAik: Then… another table is there, 3 tables are there. Let me see, okay, and 4 tables, 5 tables. I feel that this would be a good benchmark that we can put.
Krish NAik: This is at least better than yesterday, yes, I'm… because the bug I have fixed, actually, so I feel the performance is better than yesterday.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the other paper that I am testing. I'm sharing the link in the chat, whoever wants to do the test.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just try to…
Krish NAik: Make an ingestion for this one.
Krish NAik: Others, please do the testing thoroughly. That's why I'm telling you, because I know, yes, where it will fail. So, based on that, at least those things that we can fix.
Krish NAik: Because in my mind, two things is there. Any other thing that comes to your mind, please let me know.
Krish NAik: In the chat, because my options will be query transformations, Heidi, these two, any other things that you can suggest.
Krish NAik: please provide your suggestions also, because by this time in this course, I feel
Krish NAik: Really, you have gained a lot of knowledge, so you can provide me your inputs also.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me try to make an ingest for the pneumotron paper.
Krish NAik: Hold me, please.
Krish NAik: Choose a file… And landing and…
Krish NAik: This is Rajat Khanna is asking RRF to, RSF.
Krish NAik: I feel the impact will be… A little bit lower, Rajan.
Krish NAik: Because it's all about the query. If you really look into it in the query, only, like, that figure 6 and figure 7 worked, but only when I passed Figure 6 completed.
Krish NAik: So I feel that it's much more on query limit.
Krish NAik: But you are correct, so probably it can have a very small impact, RRF to RSF switch, if you buy to make it.
Krish NAik: This is having 14 pages already, the ingestion has started, let me move sooner.
Krish NAik: Okay, Mitesh is asking, CRAG,
Krish NAik: CRAG, generally, like, when I need a fallback to the internet, okay, in that case, CRAG, I feel, is better. SRAG, I can…
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: You can add CRAG and SRAG, that is fine, but CRAG, lesser preference. When I need some type of fallback systems, then I feel CRAG is better. But at least SRAG, I feel that, yes, we can do it.
Krish NAik: gonna be at, two places, caption generation and the query transformation. Yes, exactly correct. That is the core functionality.
Krish NAik: No, no, nothing with respect to, okay, now, actually, in the image captioning part, like, as Sampati was telling, evaluation metrics using RAGAS, but I feel that there we can add it. It means that, what we can do for captioning part.
Krish NAik: Like, we can use two different LLMs, okay? And then, like, the one that we feel is a much stronger LLM, we can actually check the claims.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in that way, like, I can ask, like, please generate 15 claims based on the caption results, and then we can actually do the testing.
Krish NAik: In that way, but again, it's an operational overhead, but I feel that it's much a safer way to do that, if I try to bring two multimodal elements, like one from the Gemini 3 Pro, okay, and one, like, GPT 5.4. Those are really, like, best right now.
Krish NAik: So actually, like, I can start, and then once I have the captions, those captions, I can generate the claims, and then actually I can do a cross-check.
Krish NAik: I hope you get into the approach that I'm telling right now.
Krish NAik: If you, yes?
Krish NAik: How many of you got the… idea that I'm telling you.
Krish NAik: Josh is asking difference between speculative
Krish NAik: And self-reflective grads. Self-reparatory lab, I have discussed. Speculative, what do you mean by that, Josh? Really?
Krish NAik: Please repeat, alright, the idea that I was telling, see, for captioning, I'm writing it in, Z form.
Krish NAik: Investigate.
Krish NAik: Because this idea, I can actually explore it a little bit. So, just look. Because for image captioning being dependent, so, like, I have,
Krish NAik: 1, okay?
Krish NAik: And I have another input.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in one of the places I am using, let's take 5.4 from the family of GPTs, and MM2 is Gemini 3.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Now,
Krish NAik: One, for example, if I'm going ahead, my final captions, so here also I'll be generating the captions.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: And here, also, I'll be generating the captions.
Krish NAik: Now, let's take… okay, now what I will do, in the next step, the captions here, which have been generated by Gemini. So, I'll be actually looking into the claims.
Krish NAik: I'll be creating… how many of you remember the evaluation part? Anybody remembered? Like Ragas, whenever we are doing any faithfulness, in that case, we used to generate claims.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, bring it down from the actual, caption. So here, I'll be generating multiple claims. So, let's take, like, 10 to 15 claims that I'm generating.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this claims needs to be cross-verified with the caption output.
Krish NAik: Gpt 5.4.
Krish NAik: Similarly, you can use same LLM from the same family, but I'm telling you, this is one idea.
Krish NAik: Then, in that way, I feel that it's better.
Krish NAik: LLM as a judge, yes, exactly. The approach is that only.
Krish NAik: Because I am using another LLM.
Krish NAik: I hope you get the approach, everybody. It's not about sentences, there can be a lot of cross-cushioning around that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so then finally, we can actually, get into how many the total claims are supported. Like, if I say, like, less than 50% or 60% or 70% of the claims are supported, then only I will make it as an caption. If it is less than 70%, I will discard it.
Krish NAik: Yes, you got it?
Krish NAik: everybody, the approach. Because, see, really, this part is where I feel this is a bottleneck, really, and you really need to solve. So, yes, LLM is a church-based approach.
Krish NAik: So that's any other ideas that you have in your mind? Because this part, nobody discusses, actually, any recent papers or any multi-modal-based solution. They will directly say that they have done the captioning.
Krish NAik: And really, like, I don't feel that, that part, because this is how to play safe around, I feel.
Krish NAik: But, any other approaches from your side, you guys can let me move the chat, okay? I will open the chat for everyone.
Krish NAik: Attendees can chat with Andy.
Krish NAik: Rajat is asking… graph rag?
Krish NAik: You want to implement GraphFrag only for what? Only for the image tables for your multimodal data. Rajat, are you talking about?
Krish NAik: All right, that is fine, but, just, again, you have to maintain two databases, then.
Krish NAik: Because, it's an overhead, because once you were using VectorTV, then from VectorTV, you were switching there. I feel it's an…
Krish NAik: Because, really, like, with cost comps, I can say that you can try that.
Krish NAik: And it will work off.
Krish NAik: But, again, like, how to stick to vector deviate tools?
Krish NAik: thing from that one, because then I feel that my entire solution, I will keep it in graph, right? Then why to go with vector team?
Krish NAik: So, that's why, again, using two different ones, it's fine. Hybrid-based architectures, as I told you, now hybrid becomes so much of hybrid.
Krish NAik: But, okay, this approach, any other approaches from your perspective, please let me know.
Krish NAik: anyone. Because this is, somewhere that…
Krish NAik: I feel the image captioning needs to be verified at this.
Krish NAik: If I'm…
Krish NAik: Alright, let me just check whether the captioning is done.
Krish NAik: God of Ashen Failed on October.
Krish NAik: check your, ULAMA. If something, like, if there is some issue with respect to Ulama, you can get it.
Krish NAik: So, here, updated 51 points to collection document. I feel that, this is done, the pneumotron paper that I have passed, okay? So, now, everybody have made this, ingestion for the Nemotron paper, please let me know.
Krish NAik: I've already shared the paper, the link to you, I think you guys can make an interest in this paper. A lot of tables are there. So my focus is little bit toward the tables now.
Krish NAik: Because image testing, we have done it, and we know the comps.
Krish NAik: Now, it's working for some tables, and for, some it's not. Okay, alright. Let me test,
Krish NAik: Because I feel that in multimodal solution, this is one thing.
Krish NAik: Like, when you are actually keeping the information also for tables, like, how you want to structure that
Krish NAik: Because yes, it has to be an atomic unit.
Krish NAik: It means that the entire information has to be inside a single chunk.
Krish NAik: It doesn't matter how many tokens are there, actually, I cannot break it into multiple chunks.
Krish NAik: But, like, the size of the chunk team.
Krish NAik: Okay, is it working for, languages for… No public space.
Krish NAik: Alright, what is the modality and the languages for profitable cooking? Let me do the testing with pneumotron paper now.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let's start, with… The first table, alright.
Krish NAik: Num… This is the name of the datasets that we have.
Krish NAik: multimodal…
Krish NAik: multilingual OCR, modalities. And, I've… want, okay, now thing.
Krish NAik: Oh… Because the filter modality part leave it for now, okay?
Krish NAik: modalities.
Krish NAik: Because, if I directly pass this particular question…
Krish NAik: Okay, so again, let me just open it.
Krish NAik: It's taking assumption from the context, where are these assumptions coming from? Assumptions, what are the assumptions that you are telling, Rahul?
Krish NAik: Above cushion. No, no, no, I just picked up something, a keyword from the table directly, I have passed it.
Krish NAik: There are no assumptions or anything. I've just copy-pasted it from the, main one.
Krish NAik: No, no, no. So, which one? No, no, you are telling which fact?
Krish NAik: I will…
Krish NAik: Okay, you are asking this query. Evaluation results on an internal test set and provide the best method.
Krish NAik: from NVIDIA.
Krish NAik: Like, you want me to test this particular query.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me pass it.
Krish NAik: Evaluation results on internal test.
Krish NAik: and provide Cool.
Krish NAik: But let me see. Even I'm not sure.
Krish NAik: Hmm… Just wait. Looks like a disconnection part.
Krish NAik: But I can see that, in the results, I got something like, I don't have enough context right now. So, assumption that you are telling.
Krish NAik: So… let me just check.
Krish NAik: Because the assumption part, when I look into… That's great.
Krish NAik: Because I'm getting the correct chunk, actually, because I feel the ranking of the results are really good.
Krish NAik: Because of that, I'm getting the current chunk ID.
Krish NAik: So just wait, let me start sharing the screen again. I think the power is back.
Krish NAik: This is extra… 3, okay. Now, if you look into the results, based on that, I can say that, yes, table 2 evaluation results on an internal set.
Krish NAik: Multilingual with additional data. Now, this is what's coming.
Krish NAik: Now, this is based on that particular release.
Krish NAik: Can you suggest for, okay, I'm getting a completely different answer with assumptions. With assumptions.
Krish NAik: Like, please have a check on the keyword, because the idea is that the poor content will be always
Krish NAik: From the PDF. In the PDF, is there something like assumption-based keywords?
Krish NAik: Please have it checked on.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that if something is there, then only it will come. Because right now, I know that the retrieval is fine.
Krish NAik: And the result that I'm getting… okay, this is, one.
Krish NAik: children.
Krish NAik: Any other… let me, try to ask some other questions, okay?
Krish NAik: Okay, this is table 2 information that I have, evaluations on the internal set.
Krish NAik: Find… let me, look into it. Because I know in some places, it will fail for sure.
Krish NAik: on GNOT, okay?
Krish NAik: Let me try to pass this as a cushion.
Krish NAik: Because in multimodality, really, the handling of the data, it's much tougher.
Krish NAik: Because…
Krish NAik: One, there is no, I can say, this is a foolproof direct solution, at least. I know that one modality, the same thing for second modality, really doesn't work.
Krish NAik: So, that's why.
Krish NAik: Because thorough testing needs to be done. So let me just pass, like, what…
Krish NAik: are among the Osular metrics in Juity.
Krish NAik: Hmm, alright.
Krish NAik: Table 3, OCR metrics on GeoT benchmark, okay? So, yes, I'm getting the information directly if I ask something. Now, let me try to pick up an element from the table.
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: Let me try to frame a question from here directly.
Krish NAik: Let me try to create a complex, reasoning-based question, okay?
Krish NAik: West Hunch.
Krish NAik: create some questions from this particular table, which I can ask my multimodal rack system for testing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's see. From this table, I'm just creating some complex questions, whether it's working or not.
Krish NAik: Others, give me the docklink GO2 benchmark results, and give me the Docklink GO2 benchmark results.
Krish NAik: Because this is an exact information. If it is not embedded in the caption, it cannot answer.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I can see the blue score for Mestral is 0.9560. Let me do the verification from the table.
Krish NAik: Mmm… 0.9560.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. Element base directly I picked up. It's working. Most others you shared gave me the Docklink GOT benchmark results for OCR, alright. Let me test this one.
Krish NAik: And Duckling, duckling, where is that one?
Krish NAik: In this case, it's failing form.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the dockling… Okay, now let me just try to reframe the question.
Krish NAik: You can let me sleep.
Krish NAik: Because this is Table 3 entries coming, and actually, when I look into… see, the information that you are looking, do you think that in this, particular modality, you have that, dockling-based information? Because that is also important.
Krish NAik: And I can see right here, in some case, can you see that the results of the OCR?
Krish NAik: here, like, 24.24.24.24. So somehow I feel the result of the, OCR.
Krish NAik: It is, a little bit towards the downside. It's not exactly the correct one.
Krish NAik: So, always try to analyze, not only based on the results, exactly, you have to look into the OCR results also.
Krish NAik: They also play a crucial role. I can see here a lot of 24, 24, 24 here, pneumotron pass 11111. Can you actually see this?
Krish NAik: And, here, let me try to reframe that. Because, yes, somehow the performance of the OCR, here it failed.
Krish NAik: Let me try to ask something much more exactly from table-based, okay?
Krish NAik: Because, yes, in some cases it's working, but at least better than before. I can say some improvements have been there.
Krish NAik: Okay, what is the meteospore of marker? Let me see whether it can respond or not. The meteospore of marker is 0.975.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, little bit, more complex question from a sample table, let me try to take it. List all the metrics from the Landing AI document agent.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me see whether it works or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, the landing AI document agent, let me see, because here I feel that, again, it will fail.
Krish NAik: Because if… but again, the metrics are OCR, text only, it's working. I can say the performance is at least better than yesterday.
Krish NAik: But in some cases, it's failing. So, really, with respect to the table-based information, okay, we need to work, because, yes, this is the actual HTML conversion. It means that the output that comes, it's in the HTML format.
Krish NAik: Now, that HTML we are passing, and I can say that, yes, somehow, the performance is better. So, please, guys, do the testing for tables.
Krish NAik: And then let me.
Krish NAik: Because in front of you, I'm doing thorough testing.
Krish NAik: It takes from… let's try to take,
Krish NAik: Pneumotron pass 1.1 and 1.tc, okay?
Krish NAik: That token com… The… compute one version, alright. Let me try to pass this version.
Krish NAik: Let me see whether this works or not.
Krish NAik: the comparison, and it's working, I can say.
Krish NAik: much better, because last class, it was really… So, please do the testing, and then let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay, Rahul, you are getting this to provide a comprehensive answer. I will need to make some assumptions about the context, as the question is quite broad. Typically, when discussing. So, what is the question that you passed, Rahul? The same question that you… evaluation test result that you sent to me.
Krish NAik: Is that the one?
Krish NAik: Because it's working for me, in your case.
Krish NAik: Because it's a small question only that you have asked, so I feel that
Krish NAik: Should work, because for me, Of course, while this is coming, really, it's…
Krish NAik: Hard to say. Now, this information should not be anywhere around your chart.
Krish NAik: And I have kept it, like, directly. If it doesn't understand, it will simply show that I don't have enough context.
Krish NAik: Now, why that game?
Krish NAik: Which LLM you are using, Rahul, let me know.
Krish NAik: Because, yes, these are some edge cases that comes around. So, exactly, are you using GPT-4 only?
Krish NAik: GPT-4O or GPT-4?
Krish NAik: Please tell me the exact one.
Krish NAik: Okay, you're using GPT-4, then it's actually the same.
Krish NAik: Little bit,
Krish NAik: 0.0 complaint.
Krish NAik: I can see that TS, that, from this table, I'm doing the testing, I feel that TS, it's coming good.
Krish NAik: Okay, because right now, the Table 3 testing that I have done… let's take a bigger table right now, the table 4, because in Table 4, really, a lot of information is there. Let me try to generate.
Krish NAik: Others, please let me know the experience. As compared to yesterday, what is the experience today, when you are actually asking questions from the table, because it's important.
Krish NAik: Because yesterday, it was feeling a lot.
Krish NAik: because till now, I have not changed the LLM, that will be another. Those things are last resort, moving to better LLM. But before moving to LLMs, what all improvements that we can do, then…
Krish NAik: Because that's why, like, do the testing, then we will discuss the architecture. Exactly, the chunking architecture, okay, the caption generation, those things that we'll be discussing. Because then, next week, code discussion and deployment that will be working.
Krish NAik: Yes, code workflow will do, no. Code discussion is lab, deployment is lab, don't worry.
Krish NAik: We have time, that's why.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that this will be, your last project, that's why I want you guys to do a thorough testing.
Krish NAik: Okay, find out the use cases, like, if you can actually create a simple doc, keep it that these are the test cases which are failing in that way, because after this, your last project will be based on agent, so their agent tick rag will come.
Krish NAik: Okay, and not, like, this time, without agents. So I want you guys to come up that, okay, now, these are the things.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in that way, at least we can start working on fixing the bugs. I hope everybody gets it.
Krish NAik: It's not like that. When I'm creating something in one shot, everything will be working. Pretty much an incremental process. With respect to queries, we need to make fixes, fixes, fixes.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me see… okay, so, hashr project done, new abhijit.
Krish NAik: Yesterday, we did the project setup, today we are doing the thorough testing. After that, we'll discuss the architecture, deployment next week. Okay, core discussion also, like, next week.
Krish NAik: Project 5, like, I am planning for an agentic grad-based.
Krish NAik: Rather than, like, poor reviews, something like that.
Krish NAik: Because we would review things, I feel that, for that, file system, these systems are much better, that's fine.
Krish NAik: at least agentic RAG, I feel once it's done, then, like, we can take it. Do you write test cases for RAG? Yes, generally, like, test cases are there, even you can check my master branch, I have added those tests.
Krish NAik: If you want to, I think, close to 80 or 70 test cases aren't…
Krish NAik: Alright, now let me try to take ask questions from this one, because…
Krish NAik: Really, let me see that the table part is working on.
Krish NAik: What dose?
Krish NAik: Yeah, I mean, done…
Krish NAik: Alright, here I can see that, with respect to Deep Sync OCR tiny. Now, this particular keyword, when I'm looking into, I can see that again. Here, DeepSync OCR tiny didn't came in the first chunk.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… and mortality is table, I can see, but this, table is actually broken into two parts, because when I… I'm showing you, it's broken into two parts. The first part, with respect to deep, OCR, tiny, this one, so probably the metrics.
Krish NAik: With respect to, alright, let me see, Deep Sea Bosier Tiny, what other information that I can get, because here are the captions, but if you look into Nimotron parts.
Krish NAik: This is the entire table that I have passed it.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is, again, the marker one.
Krish NAik: This is with respect to the table.
Krish NAik: This is Thrawn.
Krish NAik: our main page 8, okay? So, try to, make… because in the last table, it was working, now this table is a little bit more longer. So, in that case, what happens? Let me look into only deep-seq OCR tiny keyword.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for DeepSeaQCR, exactly what is the metric which is getting calculated? Let me see… Here are tokens.
Krish NAik: So, 10 users, let me pass out.
Krish NAik: Alright, I will do that, later on, just wait, so…
Krish NAik: Because right now, for this table, let me try to do it.
Krish NAik: What?
Krish NAik: Because this deep-seq hyphen OCR hyphen time it till now…
Krish NAik: I have not got it, but let me look into a direct token-based usage information.
Krish NAik: Actually, what happens now? So, now, this particular table, now, from here, I feel that this information will be actually lost, because this table is a little bit more complex, so let me see.
Krish NAik: What is the response that I am getting?
Krish NAik: But I can see that the DeepSeaWors here tiny uses 64 tokens.
Krish NAik: Really, the answer is fixifu.
Krish NAik: Okay, it worked.
Krish NAik: All right, because I didn't thought it will work, but, really, with respect to that, testing, it really worked.
Krish NAik: Methods…
Krish NAik: Let me check, with a different model name this time, and let me see that whether it's working.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that it has to be much, more exact information. Rather than anything passing it, it becomes harder, actually, to fetch it.
Krish NAik: Because last time I just passed a single keyword.
Krish NAik: And it was. This is 795 tokens, and really, the response is coming.
Krish NAik: Alright, with respect to tokens.
Krish NAik: Okay, now let me try to make it what is the… Overall's food.
Krish NAik: Okay, because there is an overall column, but really, with respect to the metrics, so I have just passed pool. Let me see that whether it can be fetch the results 0, 1,
Krish NAik: 0.127 or not.
Krish NAik: 0.127, it's working.
Krish NAik: Much, much better, I can say, as compared to, because last time it was not working. But, please, others, do the testing and let me know.
Krish NAik: Try to keep your question much more in the form of interrogative sentences.
Krish NAik: If I try to make it formula score, overall, I will change it to download, add formula here.
Krish NAik: Let me see whether I'm getting it or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, now here it failed.
Krish NAik: Because the formula one, I can see that here, 0.269, the answer should come, but here it failed.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me try to deep-seek out here.
Krish NAik: Let me see, because score is something like I'm adding that, from my side, But again, but
Krish NAik: Yes, here it is. Because in some questions, when you are actually very specific, in some cases it's failing, in some cases it's working.
Krish NAik: Let's look into the table score ones.
Krish NAik: Because, I feel that, we can actually save each row-level information also, like, when we are actually creating that table-based information.
Krish NAik: That is the other way around. Okay, here it's spelling that, compare the stimility score of various methods, ranging from 76, 92
Krish NAik: This is a figure table.
Krish NAik: Now this is page number 9.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is coming from this one. This is just… now, this is actually a different table information. So here I feel that the re-ranking that I asked.
Krish NAik: That is only wrong.
Krish NAik: Okay, but I… And I'll…
Krish NAik: this particular information that I have, again, a text one. So, like, the table information is also coming here. I can see the text, the table comparisons, so I can see that, yes, the chunk is there in my top 5 selection.
Krish NAik: this is your entire table information that I have it. So I feel that, with respect to the generation, somehow we need
Krish NAik: Now, what is the solution see? Here, really, I feel that we cannot keep a limit that, for your multimodal, that this should be. Okay, we have to increase the max number of tokens in the output.
Krish NAik: Because generally, I'm keeping it under 512 tokens always, but I feel that, that particular thing, probably let's keep it much higher, 2048 or 409 cents, at least.
Krish NAik: Because in the result generation part, if I try to add a cap.
Krish NAik: Okay, then the quality of the results is actually going down. That's how.
Krish NAik: Table extraction, table extraction accuracy, this is another one.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, Let me just try with that one.
Krish NAik: No, the filter modality.
Krish NAik: Because really, we have not tested that one, but modality… Definitely.
Krish NAik: Filter underscore modality.
Krish NAik: And let me pass, table.
Krish NAik: Because most of the times, when the system is failing, I'm not having the information in the captions.
Krish NAik: How many of you are actually looking into the chance and the re-ranking order? You'll let me know.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, guys, in the chat.
Krish NAik: Jason is, okay, have I missed any comma? Yeah.
Krish NAik: Now, can you say it worked? See, the same thing, last time it didn't work. But once I added the filter modality, it worked.
Krish NAik: Okay, I feel that, yes, it's picking up, because this is exactly what I was looking for, but last time it was not working, because that's why, actually, I added the test there, very specifically.
Krish NAik: Alright, okay.
Krish NAik: Let me check the formula part also. Last time, formula was not working, let me see.
Krish NAik: Now, this is also coming.
Krish NAik: Okay, because very specifically, right now, I have removed every information of text, and right now, I'm only focusing on table-based information.
Krish NAik: I hope, like, this actually helps you to getting much more refined result.
Krish NAik: Yes, how many of you understood, like, what I have done? A very small change. I'm only picking up the chunks which are related to tables, and I am, disregarding the others which are related to text. In that way, I feel that at least the system is performing better through that.
Krish NAik: please, use the filter modality, and then let me know when you are actually asking, please switch on this particular option. Because last time, also, for images, I have not done it. I know that actually it will help you to get better results. But do the testing.
Krish NAik: Now, wherever it was failing, you guys can let me know in the chat, okay? Now, this is not working, you can share it with me.
Krish NAik: And then I think, after 10 minutes, we will start discussing the core application architecture, all the mermaid workflows that, we have.
Krish NAik: Okay, now Saurabh is asking, I have sent,
Krish NAik: kind request to using the PDF I have sent, alright? Where you have sent the PDF, sorry.
Krish NAik: on my email.
Krish NAik: Email you have sent it.
Krish NAik: Alright, I need to do, like, just look.
Krish NAik: Hi, I got the preview.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is, reply for pre-made quills, alright.
Krish NAik: Okay, the orientation is different, let me change the orientation.
Krish NAik: Last week, it could… I have to change the orientation, because that operation…
Krish NAik: We don't have it here today.
Krish NAik: The orientation is this one. I have to move it in the right direction.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, this is a simple orientation detection. Any algorithm from OpenCV can do.
Krish NAik: Others, please, let me know, because I feel that, right now, through the filters, it's better.
Krish NAik: Now, one… Okay, let's go with what are those.
Krish NAik: Directly, let me pass it.
Krish NAik: Emote 1 par 3800 tokens per second. I feel that the information is coming better right now.
Krish NAik: Alright, so Maiselie, I feel that, this is performing better as compared to the other two modalities, I've done the filtration, and it's working. But yes, again, in some cases, it's not working off.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I will do a final test.
Krish NAik: I feel that, here, the information that I have in the contributors, for a W-E-R.
Krish NAik: the English language.
Krish NAik: What is the Epson score on English?
Krish NAik: language.
Krish NAik: Nope.
Krish NAik: All right, now, when I look into the chunk, the piece of text, the table compares the word error and the F1 score of different languages, indicating the performance of a language system.
Krish NAik: But, here I feel that the information with respect to English is there within the captions.
Krish NAik: Generally, with respect to text, because in some cases, the information is there, and 0.03
Krish NAik: And the F1 score.
Krish NAik: F1 score value that I have, English is 0.098.
Krish NAik: But it's there in the caption, but it actually missed this time, so this is a classic case. Again, I feel that this is not…
Krish NAik: Alright, so I know that yes, few cons are there. It's working. What is the F1 score in English language? You are getting it. Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Well, right now, Saurabh, shared me one PDF with me. Okay, now I will do the testing. Quickly, let me just do that.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me do an ingestion for that particular file. Do you have any questions, or I'll copy-paste those questions with me.
Krish NAik: 100%.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the type of document you have?
Krish NAik: This is…
Krish NAik: This is actually a scanned document. Generally, for digital PDFs, GLM OCR is better. You need to switch your poor OCR engine, because for scanned PDFs, like, you need to work out with PP detection.
Krish NAik: Okay, the actual, paddle Paddle BOCR, so please do change the OCR engine, because GLM OCRs are for digitalized videos.
Krish NAik: Alright, so that is one thing, but let me do the testing for now.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine, let me choose the file.
Krish NAik: I think, this is the document that you have shared with me.
Krish NAik: Overwrite, fine, 512.
Krish NAik: I've added an ingestion, it will take 3-4 minutes.
Krish NAik: After this, we will start with the, discussion of the application flow and the architecture, the mermaid workflows one by one.
Krish NAik: Because I feel there is no standardization in the response that we are getting in. Because we can standardize the structure, but exactly the piece of text.
Krish NAik: So I feel that, for table-related, I feel that, like, like, column-wise and row-wise information, I need to group it.
Krish NAik: summer. That, in that way, I can know that the retrieval will be better.
Krish NAik: Because right now, I'm not doing any rule-level information, or, that one.
Krish NAik: There's so… here…
Krish NAik: Modality counts. Total, there are 19 tables. I'm really not sure about Saurabh. Okay, you can go through one image is there, and really, really, very less amount of text. Okay, so what type of question you want me to ask?
Krish NAik: Any coupons this week for Course? No, no. Actually, I don't know how many of you know that Udemy and Coursera
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: the integration of both the organizations, the merger, I hope everybody knows.
Krish NAik: After the merger, okay, it's like, every feature that they have, free coupons, everything that they have removed. No such things right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why. After the merger, Pulsara team came and they have removed everything.
Krish NAik: No such features, so that's why.
Krish NAik: Saurabh, you are asking no idea, you only shared the document, you have no idea about the questions.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine, let me look into…
Krish NAik: You should have some idea, that's why…
Krish NAik: Just wheat.
Krish NAik: Yes, I'm generating through GPT some questions.
Krish NAik: From random people.
Krish NAik: Now, the cursor will increase the UWM price, it was very… it won't increase the price by a lot.
Krish NAik: But yes, there will be some increase in the margin.
Krish NAik: All right, based on some clauses that I can see, okay, let me just try to frame a question there.
Krish NAik: But it's sold.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I asked a question from, this one. Clause 6.163, disclaimer.
Krish NAik: Really? Okay, so here… States that that contractor acknowledges. You can see the table is working, sir.
Krish NAik: Okay? Your testing done. But actually, I will say that GLM OCR is better for digitalized, so you can do the testing on that.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I'm telling you the open source solutions, like, if you can go ahead with your actual cloud-based APIs, the same things will go.
Krish NAik: GLM is better, because even in the research technical report, they say that,
Krish NAik: For digital PDFs, better, so I feel that.
Krish NAik: Whereas, like, the parallel OCR wheel test is about for scanned documents and everything, it's fine.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm telling.
Krish NAik: It's according to their technical rules. But, it's working. You can later on do the testing.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. We have done a lot of testing today. Now,
Krish NAik: People who have done there, like, whatever the bulk that you have noticed, keep it in one place, and then share it with me.
Krish NAik: I think somewhere you have written that this didn't work, this didn't work, at least in your clipboard history, some is there. Keep it in one place.
Krish NAik: Because then, again, I will do a thorough testing, and somehow I feel the more level of standardization is required with respect to captions, because in some cases it fails, in some cases. Because I felt that, though, the information was there in captions, but again…
Krish NAik: Because, my last options are changing the LLM, introducing IDN query transformation, but before them, what we can do.
Krish NAik: And,
Krish NAik: Viraj, see, the main purpose of using the Gina AI re-ranker is that it's an API-based call. Otherwise, what I have to do, locally, I have to run the quin re-ranker VL model, because this is a multi-metallic project, so I have taken VL, the Vision Support ReRankers.
Krish NAik: There are text-free rankers, and there are visionary rankers. For visionary rankers, again, you need more GPUs. Then, probably, I need to go ahead with an L40S, with a 48GB of VR.
Krish NAik: Okay, even if I'm going with the 2 billion parameter. That's the only thing. GINAR gives you direct API access of that VL model.
Krish NAik: Okay, later on, you can switch to Quinn.
Krish NAik: Okay, Viraj, you were asking, but in our case, we are doing captioning on the image, so at the end, we are dealing with text only. Yes, at the end, you are dealing with text only.
Krish NAik: Actually, like, there is an option of sending the base64 also.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you really look into, quadrant, you are… okay, here you will see,
Krish NAik: Because when I'm actually saving the images, okay, for the images, I'm saving base 64. Actually, I can tag that particular information also to the VA.
Krish NAik: PL understands the base64, whereas your text models won't be doing that.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you can actually return… can you see here? There is a page 64 that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally for your images, I'm saving all the image base 64, so that later on, if you need the GT for that particular information, you can actually send it to a VL, re-rank government.
Krish NAik: So that is, the added benefit. But, every time returning base 64, it becomes a pain, because the base 64 value is very, very long.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now I think we have done enough testing, so everybody, please do switch up your studios. Okay, and let me know the cases where it's very much failing, because I feel that text, every time it's working, but very specifically, like.
Krish NAik: When you go internally and asking a very thick, very specific question, row-level or column-level question, in some cases, it's failing.
Krish NAik: So, those cases, really, I feel that, a column-level information or an exact HTML that I should attach, it means that with the captions, even send the HTML also.
Krish NAik: to the, Llm.
Krish NAik: Because right now, I was not sending, actually, the HTML of the markdown files.
Krish NAik: sorry, marked, yes, the markdown, the HTML markdown. Because the OCR, shared the results with you in an HTML-based format, or basically the markdown-based format. So that particular entire table information also you can set it.
Krish NAik: But, if the results of the OCR is wrong, then again, nothing that we can do from our end.
Krish NAik: Alright, so… let me go back and switch off the studios for now. So, I feel that we have done it. So you guys can,
Krish NAik: Let me know now exactly the part in the switch of the students.
Krish NAik: Alright, let's go for a 10-minute break, and then we'll continue, okay?
Krish NAik: Motas are exactly correct. If later on in the UI, if you want to render that particular image as your GT, it becomes
Krish NAik: Much better. So that's why I'm saving the base64, because the base64 is thrown, by the OCR model, okay, with their bounding box coordinates. So I feel that… keep that information. Later on, it is always helpful.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine, let's go for a 10 minutes break. Okay, so what's the time now? It's 10.55, so let's start after 10.
Krish NAik: In the meantime, any type of questions that we want is done. Switch up, yeah, yeah, switch off, switch off the studio, because right now, studio is not required.
Krish NAik: And even for our deployments, like, right now I have used the GPUs, later on, I'll be switching to GPU, like, CPUs. CPUs with more, I can say, memory-optimized instances, that, rather than, like,
Krish NAik: compute-optimized instances that I will pick up.
Krish NAik: Because for my Ullama to be running, I feel… Mmm…
Krish NAik: Really, at least I'll feel that we need, 16GB of RAM.
Krish NAik: At least, for a single container also fine, doesn't.
Krish NAik: Because directly running ULAMA, it really requires a lot of infrastructure.
Krish NAik: First of all, we'll be talking about the architecture method, don't worry. So, core discussion will be there, your deployment, those two things, I think next week we can do.
Krish NAik: First of all, the flow with respect to the chunking, the captioning, those things we'll be talking about.
Krish NAik: So, in your local, I think everybody has taken the Git pull, and you guys have the mermaid workflow.
Krish NAik: Please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Every month.
Krish NAik: Yes, please let me know. Everyone is back.
Krish NAik: Then we'll continue with the… discussions of the mermaid workflows.
Krish NAik: I think, and the mermaid workflows are in the master branch.
Krish NAik: Yes, it is in the master branch.
Krish NAik: You can say it all went.
Krish NAik: Alright, the portions image, we are showing it fine.
Krish NAik: Viraj, second, in our case, we are doing captioning. We are sending both the information, Viraj, okay? The actual base 64 also, okay, with the captions.
Krish NAik: Because, you have to understand the base64 is, viewed by two things. One is your GPT-40, pixel-by-pixel analysis that it does, as well as your, GINA VL re-ranker. That also. In that case, also, you are binding the complete image Base64.
Krish NAik: But, in your case, if you just think about if you are actually working with text, in that case, it really doesn't matter.
Krish NAik: But if you are working with images in that case.
Krish NAik: Because in the backend, when we are actually packaging the data and sending it, so there we are sending the base64 for the image modalities.
Krish NAik: I hope, where are you getting?
Krish NAik: Mmm, okay, in which branch, alright. So, let's continue.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first of all, I've tried to break it into all the necessary, Major League workflows, so that's why 10 to 14 workflows that we have. So, first of all, like, this is the overall system one. Quickly, I think we can go through, like, PDF for the image.
Krish NAik: Open source. So, what are the recommended OCRs? Which is, I talked about a lot of OCRs.
Krish NAik: Because right now, in March, like, in this month, a lot of OCRs came. Like, GLM technical report came, so I implemented the GLM one.
Krish NAik: Other than that, Chandra OCR2, really good one. Rednote team, OCR, they also launched it with MOCR support. That is also a good one.
Krish NAik: Okay, then, yesterday, I was actually looking into that one, the…
Krish NAik: VINU OCR, that was also having good benchmarks.
Krish NAik: Okay, so really, like, Just check the Omni
Krish NAik: benchmark, the only document, the OCR benchmark. Okay, so from there, you will get… and every month, some OCR comes. So, I feel that right now, it's better that you can actually…
Krish NAik: So, I found GLM hour and our Nemotron hour useful. Okay, Nimotron parse is good, but remember, in some cases, again, some H cases are there.
Krish NAik: Okay, and generally, with respect to text and other things, it really worked, because it's a unified model.
Krish NAik: Okay, in unified models, I feel that, they are lesser, better as compared to if you use two different things, highly specialized, like one layout detection model with one.
Krish NAik: Because till now, the research shows that a single unified model is not so much good as compared to if you use two separate entities.
Krish NAik: Ashok is asking, I could not find the system overview MD. Please do have a chat, and do a get poll. If you don't do a GET pull, today only I have pushed the code.
Krish NAik: any OCRs, like, generally, I feel that in open source, Paddle OCR is one of my main preference, which I've been using for more than…
Krish NAik: 3 to 4 years. And really, it's called patent money.
Krish NAik: If you ask me in the open source community, but other OCRs are also coming up.
Krish NAik: And as I've done the testing, Chandra Osi are really good.
Krish NAik: Okay, red note also, I've tested, that is also good.
Krish NAik: Enterprise, Mestral, OCR, then other, everyone. AWS, API, TechStrack, Talk Intelligence, those things really works out. If you are actually looking directly, not for an open source, an enterprise.
Krish NAik: Fine, so let's start, first of all, with the system overview. Okay, so here, the pipeline has main four sequential phases. The first path is the parsing part. So, during our parsing, what are the things that we need?
Krish NAik: To make our parser work, everybody, please let me know the paradigm B.
Krish NAik: That we have discussed in the last week.
Krish NAik: What is that?
Krish NAik: In the paradigm B.
Krish NAik: Okay? Always remember two things, layout, detection plus OCR.
Krish NAik: Okay? Two things. Now, that is the path. Otherwise, we cannot do the parsing only. So, layout plus OCR. Okay? So, that's why you'll be ingesting any type of PDF slash image.
Krish NAik: Then comes, your two main, grades file. One is the GLM one.
Krish NAik: through OLAMA, we are accessing it, and PP.Cloud, a direct implementation through Hug Inflace transformers that we are actually accessing it.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, the total, written type of all the elements, like, 23 element categories that I have. 23 element categories, it means, like, paragraph, title.
Krish NAik: Page number, okay, you can think about images, tables, algorithms, formulas, everything. So, all those elements.
Krish NAik: So, elements… I hope everybody gets that. Element.
Krish NAik: So, similarly, like, every, one has their own, so if I show you, if you really want to know about the elements, so let's take, PP, talk, layout.
Krish NAik: I think, V3?
Krish NAik: Okay, let's go into the fine motions.
Krish NAik: We need to make files.
Krish NAik: Okay, at least this will give you a high-level idea with respect to the elements that I'm talking about.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, something like this, an abstract detection, a site text. Now, this information you have in your JSON file. Yesterday.
Krish NAik: Did I show you yesterday the visualizer part? Yes, I think. Yesterday, I showed you the streamlit visualizer part. First ways to do the parsing, and then the visualization part. So, in that particular JSON file, if you remember, inside the ulama folder that I had.
Krish NAik: I showed you the JSON file, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay? You can actually always go through that. SOM is asking the 23 element categories according to the paddle CR unhugging phase. R…
Krish NAik: The 23 categories are… Okay, you shared a book. Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, but I'm telling you, like, you can always get these type of information directly through Hugging Face, based on that, okay? So, roughly around, based on this particular… so directly, I went to the Wix one, and I have showed you. So, similarly, you can always have a look into whichever detection layout that you are actually selecting.
Krish NAik: Literally.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, let's get back here.
Krish NAik: Then comes, once I have the final results, okay, so then parse results. The return type, it totally depends what is the return type that you want.
Krish NAik: It can be a JSON, it can be a markdown. I've already given that option to you, if you remember the scripts.
Krish NAik: In scripts, the test scripts, so there you have the parsing one. So there I added that particular parameter also, an argument, so that if you want your return type in which format? So by default, Markdown is supported. Okay, Markdown and JSON, these two are the main return types.
Krish NAik: of your pathster. So, parser is basically the combination of both the things. Your layout detection plus easier.
Krish NAik: Now, once you have your final results from there, then I'm moving towards the document-aware chunking part.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, with respect to your, document-aware chunking, okay, I'll be talking about this little bit when I will come to this chunking architecture, okay?
Krish NAik: So, for now, I will say that this is one of the best ways to retain most of the information from your documents. So, sometimes it's called document-aware chunking, sometimes it's called layout-aware chunking, sometimes it's called structure-aware chunking.
Krish NAik: But always remember, the main theme is always the same.
Krish NAik: So don't get confused if somebody says you, what is layout of Ashanking, okay? Or, similarly, like, structure of Afshanking. The meaning will always be the same.
Krish NAik: Perfect. Now, once you have done your chunking, then, comes the enrichment of the chunk, so this is where your GPT-4U vision, very specifically that we are using.
Krish NAik: Because, during our, chunking, always remember that we have our core informations, like, your main image-based informations, and from there.
Krish NAik: Through enrichment of the chunks is basically through a captioning operation that we try to increase more information.
Krish NAik: Okay, because actually, what is there in the images? That is the main part, that's why I've written GPT-4O Vision, because we need the, very specifically, the vision capabilities, because it has both the capabilities as it's a multimodal.
Krish NAik: Then, once I have that, my final chunks, that I'll be doing the embedding, okay? And then my dense and sparse vectors, okay, and finally, my ingestion into the vector store input.
Krish NAik: Okay? In the next part, so first the parsing is done. After passing, your ingestion is done. So, two separate scripts that I have. If you look into your scripts folder, you will get
Krish NAik: For these two workflows, I have two separate scripts.
Krish NAik: Now, coming to the third one, which is the retrieval pipeline.
Krish NAik: Now, from Phase 2, Mantaj, could you explain, one and two stage again?
Krish NAik: Explain one. In stage one, I am passing a file. Now, that's, then we are initializing our parse file, the document parser. From there, we are initialing the models that we need. One is the layout detection model, one is the
Krish NAik: OCR model. Then the output of those models is basically this parse result, where we will be getting this 23 element categories, a JSON file.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, once I have that JSON file, then I can move ahead with our chunking. For chunking, I am using the document. Now, I will explain how this works in the chunking architecture mermaid workflow.
Krish NAik: Once I have that, I need the GPT-4O vision capabilities for my multimodal support, basically for the images.
Krish NAik: Because I'm sending the actual image to GPT-4, so that the GPT-4O can look into pixel by pixel.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: And, once I have the final chunks, then the embedding of the chunks is required.
Krish NAik: So there, which model we are using? OpenAI.
Krish NAik: Okay, text embedding 3 small with 1536 dimensions, and for our sparse vectors, it's pretty much BM25 implementation. I have not taken split or any multi-vector right now. And then finally, when the embedding is done, the next step is the quadrant, where we are actually saving all the embeddings.
Krish NAik: Mmm… Northada is saying I didn't get the part of the element categories.
Krish NAik: That is the, return type of a layout detection model. So, those are basically the categories. So, if you are only doing… just forget about OCR.
Krish NAik: Okay, you are first looking only into the layout detection, but that are the inference types. It means that whenever you are doing any inferencing, those are the main categories which are being shown in Hugging Face that I was shown.
Krish NAik: Moda, I hope we get that.
Krish NAik: The layout detection output only.
Krish NAik: It's pretty much the return type of the categories.
Krish NAik: Because those are the total. Now, out of that, it depends upon the document what all categories will come. Not necessarily all 23 will come.
Krish NAik: Can we safely assume that each chunk will have one image?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, Mitesh, why chunk will have one image?
Krish NAik: If you have an image chunk, then only I will say that you will be having an image.
Krish NAik: If it is only a text chunk, then how image will come?
Krish NAik: So, you cannot assume that one. Each image will have one, so each chunk will not have an image. Is this part clear, Mitesh?
Krish NAik: When you actually have the image, then only you will have the image. For a text, if you have a table, then again, not for that.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. Any more questions from, Phase 1 and Phase 2, you can simply ask me.
Krish NAik: Because then finally comes our retriever. In our retriever, it's a hybrid search, okay, directly on top of the vector DB that we are doing. And from there, read anchor.read rank on, the top K chunks that will be returned, by RRF.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this particular result, we are sending it to the JIN AI re-ranker.
Krish NAik: Okay, and whenever, in the GINA EI re-ranker, I have total 4 backends. If you look into the code, I have total 4 backends.
Krish NAik: Okay, what are those four backends? Anybody have looked into that
Krish NAik: The first one is your, like, GINA AI backend is there. The other backend that you have is your OpenAI.
Krish NAik: After that, you have your Quinn VL re-ranking model, okay, and the other one is the BGE3. BGE3 is the only one where text is there.
Krish NAik: Okay? Similarly for, GPT 4.0, we know that we can send image data. Similarly, GINA EIDRanker, I can send image data.
Krish NAik: Similarly, QuinVL re-ranker, there also I can send image data. But for VG3, I cannot send. It's only text-based re-ranker.
Krish NAik: Okay, so those are pluggable backends that you can actually play with. I think I have a separate file for that also.
Krish NAik: Okay, and once you get your final re-rank result, then come the generation phase, so where we are calling the GPT-4, and finally, we are returning the LLM answer with the charts.
Krish NAik: Okay, so Aruna is asking, are we having separate emittings for our text and images?
Krish NAik: Separate embeddings, no, not separate embeddings.
Krish NAik: We are not doing separate embeddings.
Krish NAik: We have taken a model which has already VL support, multimodal support.
Krish NAik: So, nothing to worry in that case.
Krish NAik: Melinda is asking, event text will be treated as, OCR type or PO text? No, no, no.
Krish NAik: The purpose of OCR is to get the actual text.
Krish NAik: So, the return type will be text.
Krish NAik: Because what is OCR, optical character recognition, so from there, what we do extract, text only. So, it will be directly text, Milith.
Krish NAik: Anirud, sir, we will be re-ranking the captions plus summary. Okay, alright. Don't worry, do I have the re-ranking file, otherwise I will write it.
Krish NAik: In the retrieval pipeline, let me see.
Krish NAik: pre-fetch, filter modality set.
Krish NAik: Alright, I don't have that particular information. Let me just open the notes, because from Marie Rankar, I feel that a lot of questions are coming. Let me just address them.
Krish NAik: Other than re-reactor part, anywhere you feel that, okay, see, okay, already, fine, I had a re-acting backend file also. Okay, so please do look into this pipe. Everybody open the reacting backend, then directly will get it. Otherwise, we can wait for the sequence to be completed.
Krish NAik: Okay? So here, I have the OpenAID ranker.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, can you see the image chunk, the page 64?
Krish NAik: That we can actually send it
Krish NAik: Similarly, here also, in Gina Read Anchor, we can send it. Gwen Real Anchor also, we can send the image chunks. Similarly, here also, we can send the image chunks. Everywhere. Only one place where we cannot send it is the BGE read anchor.
Krish NAik: That is only text only. So, you can see this is multimodal cloud, this is multimodal cloud, this is multimodal local via. So, I have 3 separate backends right now. We are using one only, otherwise you can later on do the testing of the application, where you are exploring the other ones also.
Krish NAik: So you can see that it's not only, I'm sending the text chunk, image chunk. Similarly, here also, directly written, so here also, I'm sending the text and the image content both.
Krish NAik: In whichever way it is there.
Krish NAik: Now, is it clear what we are actually sending it to the re-rankers? Please let me know. OpenAI, text chunk, image chunk. Here, also, I'm sending both the document. Text or image content. So, you have to think about content is actually the chunk reference only that we are taking. And this is the re-ranker MU model. The name of the model, if you want me exactly.
Krish NAik: We rank our MO. This has the VL support.
Krish NAik: BGA, this is only text-based, right here.
Krish NAik: what it uses, only the image captions that we have in this particular case. But this model cannot really understand an image, because it doesn't have the vision capabilities only. Again, coming to PennVL ranker, again, it has the capabilities for image chunks, where it actually looks into the image base 60 foot.
Krish NAik: Is this part clear for everyone?
Krish NAik: the rear anchor part, that's why I showed you. The 4 backends that we have. Out of those 4 backends, 3 supports multimodal, and 1 supports text.
Krish NAik: whenever you are doing any re-ranking, it's not like that if a model, if a re-ranker model is VL, it means that it can handle both the things, text as well as images.
Krish NAik: It's not only images it supports, so don't think in that way. Multimodal means?
Krish NAik: Both the things which can be supported by that.
Krish NAik: No, it's a re-ranker model. Okay.
Krish NAik: Pretty much image-based cross-encoders.
Krish NAik: In simple terms, everyone is using image-based cross-encoders, whereas this one is a direct LLM. Other than that, these three are pure re-ranking models.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is through a prompt where I ask to do the re-ranking.
Krish NAik: Just like through a prompt, as you have seen, like a manual re-ranking-based implementation.
Krish NAik: Other than that, these three are direct models that you are using.
Krish NAik: Any other questions, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Arun is asking, when re-ranking multimodal, understand, why do we need, captions? I'm creating the captions, if you change the backend for your VG EDRanker in that case. Captions are always helpful. It's some more added information. In a high level, it will tell you.
Krish NAik: just think about, if you change the backend to BGRanker, in that case, you don't have the vision capabilities, then caption comes into the picture a rule.
Krish NAik: Please let me know anybody else with respect to the four different types of, re-ranker backends that we have.
Krish NAik: Simply, like, pretty much plug and play. I can say that you can switch to VL Read Anchor, but for that, at least use a 48GB of VRAM.
Krish NAik: Okay, in 24GB also, I felt, like, you might get OAM issues, that's why.
Krish NAik: Anituta asking, is the image re-ranker also good with text? Yes.
Krish NAik: It has both the capabilities image and text.
Krish NAik: So, I cannot say that, like, for example, if I take this LLM GPT-40, right now, I'm not using Mini, you know that in the configuration, it's actually GPT-4.0. So, can I say that the GPT-40 is only good with images, and it is bad with text? It has both the capabilities, the vision and the text.
Krish NAik: So, similarly, the re-rankers, both the things.
Krish NAik: Text, as well as images.
Krish NAik: Is the support low-resource languages? Low resource languages means, what do you refer? Low resource languages?
Krish NAik: Mmm…
Krish NAik: Because directly, I cannot say, yeah, NL, I've not done the testing with respect to that, but
Krish NAik: Because I know those V-Rankers support, majorly English.
Krish NAik: Chinese… okay, so similarly, I know, it's not, like, entirely multilingual support is there, but limited support is there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the limitations of the language, I think 8 to 10 languages that GNIA supports. Similarly, you need to choose one, according to you.
Krish NAik: Rahul is asking, are we compressing the documents based on relevance given by the DRAN? No, no, no, no, see, compressing, we are not compressing. We have the base 64 content of an image.
Krish NAik: If we have the base64, then we can directly send it, no route.
Krish NAik: Nagesh is asking, if the modality is image, are we sending both the captions?
Krish NAik: And the base64, exactly. We are sending both the information.
Krish NAik: But for embedding of, images,
Krish NAik: Actually, in the embedding part, once we have that final output from GPT-4,
Krish NAik: Okay, that we are actually doing the embedding. The entireism.
Krish NAik: All right, from…
Krish NAik: Alright, here I can see.
Krish NAik: Why we used BGRAN? Because I have kept a support only for text-based support also.
Krish NAik: Okay, because if you only work with text, and if you really don't want to pass your images.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that, going forward, if you change the entire embedding model.
Krish NAik: it will be better, because right now, I have not actually used anything like Clip, blimp.
Krish NAik: Okay, now those are purely image-based embedding models.
Krish NAik: We can use them, but right now, Gemini 3 has the support for multimodal-based embeddings.
Krish NAik: Okay, so directly in the code, we have the support for Gemini 3 also. Similarly, it's a pluggable backend that you can easily switch, if you really want to use image-based embeddings only.
Krish NAik: If we want pure support for multimodal, because as we are working with text3, embedding, it's pretty much text-based, so there I don't have the support, so that's why I'm dependent on the quality of the captions.
Krish NAik: Is this part clear? What I'm trying to say?
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay, I do have the option backend to switch to a pure multimodal-based embedding one.
Krish NAik: Okay, and that's why Gemini, the new model that came, I have added the support for that. You can simply switch it from your configuration.
Krish NAik: Because in the OpenAI family, there is not a single model which supports multimodal yet. I hope everybody knows that.
Krish NAik: text embedding 3 small, because the name is only text embedding. So I hope that you get it.
Krish NAik: But there are specialized clip versions which are used.
Krish NAik: Please… Okay, players, let me know any other questions.
Krish NAik: the image representations are better. Actually, what happens in an image-based, so you can actually, like, for example, if you want to save image-based embedding separately.
Krish NAik: Now, what happens? You have to think about, if I only want to do the filtration of images.
Krish NAik: Then, through my, collections, whenever you are doing the indexing, I can keep all my image indexing. So right now, I've added that in the text that this modality is for images.
Krish NAik: I hope I'm making sense, because right now, I need to know that this chunk is for images. Otherwise, you can keep all the images within a single collection.
Krish NAik: Okay, having the embeddings, because I feel that even the newer ones support 3072 and 1536. These are common ones. And if you feel that, really, if you want to completely change the dimensions for… then I will suggest go with a different index or with a different collection.
Krish NAik: Because this is where multiple strategies that you can play with, okay? I'm saving all the images in a different collection.
Krish NAik: Now, the question comes during your query. Can you understand that the query is from an image or a text? First of all.
Krish NAik: Because that understanding should also be there.
Krish NAik: So, I feel that, then again, you have to search on top of two collections parallel.
Krish NAik: One is your normal one.
Krish NAik: Okay, the text one, and another on top of image one.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody is getting that.
Krish NAik: Because in OpenAI, till now, no supports, but
Krish NAik: The clip model is there from OpenAI, but again, I feel that not so much good.
Krish NAik: And neither API is available.
Krish NAik: Clip, clip, these options are always there. The rates are completely free, and we can play them. But, simply you can switch to Gemini 3. Okay, that is the other way around to do that.
Krish NAik: The difference between text and image, in terms of quality, I say that,
Krish NAik: image… see, here, when you are doing the text-based operations, you are actually dependent on the captions, or the summary, Murta.
Krish NAik: Whereas, directly, you can pass the image, okay? And you can save the embeddings. So, two things are different. First, from image to text, you are converting, then saving the embeddings, and directly, you are passing the image, and then getting the embedding. So, I can say that the second is much richer.
Krish NAik: With respect to the representation.
Krish NAik: Whereas, in the first one, if there is some problem with respect to captions.
Krish NAik: I hope you understand, the quality directly drops, as we have done it in our case.
Krish NAik: Yes, please let me know, everybody.
Krish NAik: Because, because I think by next week, if you want, I can add one separate collection for images also, because you have to understand the dimension of the embeddings will be different.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, I have to take such models where I have to maintain the dimensions in both.
Krish NAik: Because, you know, whenever I'm creating a collection, I have to maintain that. So, I feel that that's, one, because Gemini, then I have to use Gemini for every time, then completely I have to make a switch from OpenAI to Gemini.
Krish NAik: Methish is asking, can you explain the captioning effect on the returable quality?
Krish NAik: Captioning effect. So simply, like, if you are asking the… any multimodal LLM to create the captions, now you are totally dependent upon the LLM.
Krish NAik: If somehow the LLM gives you a bad response, the retrieval quality will automatically drop.
Krish NAik: Yes, we can actually do the improvement, and we can move to image-based implementings completely. Competitionally more expensive task.
Krish NAik: Okay, because right now, I'll be making a Gemini call, but actually, if you ask me, like, going ahead, see, like, you can let me know, do you want an open source-based solution, or directly using Gemini? Because I have the Gemini support, but, I can move to PennVL embedding models.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you have these, models. Can you see? The VL models?
Krish NAik: These models you can actually play with.
Krish NAik: Now, they will actually help you.
Krish NAik: Now you can see the embedding dimensions. This is 2048 and 4096.
Krish NAik: In our code, this model is there, the re-ranker 2 billion model, which I'm already using it for re-ranking, but I've not selected the embedding one. Later on, if you want, I can bring this particular one.
Krish NAik: Better to go with when, alright.
Krish NAik: Then in next class, what I'm planning.
Krish NAik: Rather than using GPT, let's use the entire Quen family only.
Krish NAik: Okay, a Quen embedding model, if you really want everything open source, let's leave GPT out of the picture, and Gemini. We'll be having them as pluggable backends, but, everything to Quinn, then we can actually shift it in the next file. Okay, I will be using more RAM, so expect at least
Krish NAik: And 80GB of VRAM that I'll be using to prove. But, yes, I will be doing the entire thing, the entire infra through Docker Compose, then I can actually, like, in one container, my LLM will be running.
Krish NAik: Okay, embedding model will be running, in one, so in that way, then we can do the rest one. So next, because we can do those improvements. But for now, the core one, just focus on this.
Krish NAik: Rajit is asking for metadata, actually, like, first you have to decide the structure of metadata. Tell no, I've not taught you that part, but I'm just telling you, like, you can use any type of NER-based model, and from that chunk, you can get those type of entities.
Krish NAik: Okay, and through that, actually, you can classify your chance, okay, and keep such information. So, that is how you can… two ways, one is the lang extract way, the other one is the gleaner way.
Krish NAik: Yesterday, only Gleaner, launched a new version. I feel like… I've not tested it on metadata yet, but once I do the testing, I will let you know.
Krish NAik: Okay, so simply, like, then, in the next class, I'll be doing… I will be hosting everything in local, completely moving from cloud to local, okay?
Krish NAik: Why not Voyage 3 large? Voyage 3 Large, is it providing because,
Krish NAik: Local… I don't think Voyage 3 largest having open rates. Rahul.
Krish NAik: See, there are more than 10 ones, so voice 3 large, I have no issues with that, but does it support multimodal?
Krish NAik: Because I know in the Voyage family, there is a model which is called as Voyage Multimodal 3, I think.
Krish NAik: That is having multimodal embedding support.
Krish NAik: But I don't think Voyage 3 Large has that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please have a check, and then let you know. Because right now, as I can see in the charts, pretty much everybody is requesting for that, multimodal support intact.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine, then I will add a, embedding, because I won't be changing the code, just I'll be adding a backend for your query.
Krish NAik: Okay, and in the Docker Compose file, I need to, actually use it for hosting, so probably if you look here, for our inferencing.
Krish NAik: What I can use it. Okay, I feel that Siglang or VLLM that I will take it, because I need to keep the model running in one place.
Krish NAik: Okay, otherwise the easiest way for me will be executing it in a serverless environment, like a run pod.
Krish NAik: Okay, so RunPod is the other option for me. So you guys can let me know that, do you want a little bit of exploration about serverless GPUs, then I can show you. But again, RunPod is paid. Then again, you have to spend money there. So that's why always remember that once you start making your own offline-based solutions, the cost of the infrastructure will be a bit higher.
Krish NAik: Rahul is telling it has the best general purpose and multilingual returable quality.
Krish NAik: Alright, like, if you say, let me just look into the MTV leaderboard,
Krish NAik: Because I don't think it will be their income.
Krish NAik: Okay, it's not there, neither in… Nar… Top 10 also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please do have a check always.
Krish NAik: From the MTV leaderboard. This is the main one.
Krish NAik: before making any such statements, when you say that the best general purpose… okay, it might be good, I'm not telling it is bad, but really, with respect to benchmarks, it's not like that.
Krish NAik: Because serverless GPU is very handy for researchers, exactly.
Krish NAik: Like, I think it will be good to explore serverless. You guys can let me know, like, everybody's comfortable. You really don't need, but at least just be sure that, at least, like, $1 or $2 that we need to spend. I cannot make it completely free. You have to understand, because that is an embedding model running on that one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… Then,
Krish NAik: At least the local infrastructure cost will be less, because for Lightning AI, at least you guys don't need to do any payment.
Krish NAik: But again, you have to think, for our final deployment, because it will be, in ECS than running so many things, then we'll be making few things back to APIs, okay?
Krish NAik: So, I think then this project will go on at least till second week, I think.
Krish NAik: At least the first week or second week, as we are increasing more, things there.
Krish NAik: Oh, rightly, if somebody's publishing their own blog directly, don't believe on that.
Krish NAik: Look, everybody says that my model is good.
Krish NAik: But actually, always look into the main benchmark, sir.
Krish NAik: Research is different, and production is different, that's all.
Krish NAik: Hmm… Alright, so… and at least, for our next one… Just…
Krish NAik: Because actually, hosting the model is really easy if you, really never used
Krish NAik: then that part I will discuss, and hopefully… That's what you want.
Krish NAik: Just wait, let me just have a check that whether the new support is there or not.
Krish NAik: Then we will continue with our discussion.
Krish NAik: Alright, I'm just showing you, so in the meantime, like, if you want, then I'm just taking it as a yes, that we'll be going ahead with serverless GPUs for the next class.
Krish NAik: Because server eligibles are not provided by Mike and Cebu1.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, only, I think, Lightning AI provides serverless GPU still the time you are working. When you switch off, the machine is gone, so it's pretty much serverless.
Krish NAik: Then, modal provides it, and run pod. Then, in the next class, then I'll be using this one, okay? Just be sure, whatever the bare minimum is there. If you want to do the recharge, it's fine, otherwise just look into the tutorial that I'll be showing, okay? How to use, inference-based,
Krish NAik: repos for hosting any type of LLM or anyone. Here, I can host LLM also.
Krish NAik: Okay? So that is the added benefit. Then I really don't need to spend a lot in my own custom info.
Krish NAik: Hmm, just wait, I'm getting a call from Kresh.
Krish NAik: Alright, so Aruna is asking, okay, are we keeping the inference to images? Inference to both that we have?
Krish NAik: Okay, because we have the original base64. Now, if I have the base64, I can do any image-based stuff.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm saving the base64 in my vector deans.
Krish NAik: Just tell me, if you have the base64 in your vector database, can you convert it into an image embedding ES1?
Krish NAik: All you need to do is pick up the field and send it to the embedding model. So in our code, it's not like we have to do a lot of changes, it's just passing directly the images.
Krish NAik: All right, so now let's get back. I think we have discussed a lot about the re-ranker part, now let's move ahead with the other architectures.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think, the core system overview is done. Okay, so Phase 3 and Phase 4, let's…
Krish NAik: The full pipeline part. Now, this is the actual flow of the application with respect to FastAPI, exactly how things happen.
Krish NAik: So, when you make a call, the user will make a call to generate. So, right now, I've taken the example through generate, because this is where you'll be getting the entire answer. So, the query, the top kit, the top end, re-rank, max token, these are the major ones.
Krish NAik: I'm not taking those alternate, ones, like the optional arguments, like modality filter and, the, prompt, system prompt. Those two were pretty much optional.
Krish NAik: Now, once you pass this, it will go to the FastAPI slash generate route. Now, from there, what you have to do, the query that you are passing, it needs to be embedded.
Krish NAik: Yes or no? So, that's why embedding. Here it's written 3072, so think about, like, text embedding 3 large, as we have, so… or we can use the 1536. Now, this embedding is text-based embedding. This is not multimodal embedding, because OpenAI doesn't support multimodal yet.
Krish NAik: In 2026, March.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think, I cannot actually increase the font here. If I increase this, image will become small. Try to open it from your own side.
Krish NAik: Now, once the query embedding is done, what will happen in the next step?
Krish NAik: For that particular, the dense vector that will be created, similarly, the sparse vectors, and then finally we'll be looking into the vector TV. Okay, so from here, actually, like, pre-phase VM25 with the text dense, and now it is hitting where? The quadrant vectors too. So this is the main application flow. From there, what you will be getting?
Krish NAik: The top K candidates. Now, from here, you can see in the dotted line, in the other direction, we are getting the top K candidates.
Krish NAik: Okay, now in the next step, you will be making the re-ranking part. So, for re-ranking part, again, you'll be making the call to whichever re-ranker. So, I have a base re-ranker. Under that base re-ranker, I have 4 backends. Whichever that you are selecting, it will be going to that.
Krish NAik: Okay, now once you have the base re-ranker, from there you'll be getting your top end results, okay? The top end that you'll be getting, finally, with the re-ranking scores.
Krish NAik: Once you have that, now, that particular information, you'll be passing it to your final LLM, so as you can see, the final call, I'll be making it to GPT-4, and based on that, I'm getting the answer text. And finally, for the user query, I'm getting the response to the particular user.
Krish NAik: This is the entire thing which is happening in high level with respect to the flow of a query that you are making towards our fast API application.
Krish NAik: I've told you in high level, but try to look into the diagram.
Krish NAik: Dotted lines means the return type of a component.
Krish NAik: in the other direction, whenever you will look into. It means that everything is being handled through our web application, which is FastAPI.
Krish NAik: So everything will come to FastAPI. I hope everybody gets that.
Krish NAik: It will start from FastAPI, it will end at FastAPI.
Krish NAik: Any questions from here? Please let me know. Anyone.
Krish NAik: This is the actual query flow.
Krish NAik: here it will actually change. If you are actually going ahead with multimodal embeddings, here only I will change that.
Krish NAik: Rahul is asking how you are generating these workflow docs. I do have a prompt with him.
Krish NAik: Soham is asking, okay, sure. Only this, but see, when I'm telling multimodal embeddings, it's a single model only.
Krish NAik: But it will have that support, where directly you can send the images, and based on that, you will be having.
Krish NAik: your main image embeddings. And the dimension will be different. Always remember that dimension depends upon the model. In the next class, a little bit, I'll be talking about multimodal embeddings and the implementation, when I have something in hand. But for now, for today's scoop, it's text models only.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then, again, we will a little be doing the trace testing on images, much more.
Krish NAik: Can you share, very useful for our projects?
Krish NAik: All right, later on, I will have a look. Okay, and then Mitesh, I will tell you.
Krish NAik: Alright, I will share a gist later on, okay? Raul and Vitesh.
Krish NAik: For this particular workshop.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, generally you can add it under skills.md also, that is the other option.
Krish NAik: Fine. This is the entire, please, questions, or should I move to the next architecture?
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Can I move ahead in the next one, guys?
Krish NAik: Because this is simply the flow of the query. Next architecture is all right.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is the ingestion pipeline.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is a little bit more text that I have, and this pipeline is a bit long.
Krish NAik: What should I do? If I close this one, just…
Krish NAik: Okay, because try to open it from your side, because if I try to make a zoom, then also, really, you can see that only the text is getting one.
Krish NAik: Okay,
Krish NAik: So the first part is basically the PDF or the image that you are passing, it's going to the document pass. Okay, till this point, it is actually just like in the phase one. Now, here in the enrichment of the chance, so this is where
Krish NAik: the main call happens. So this is where your multimodal things that are taking place. Because the text, you really don't, because the text is pretty much unchanged, that I have written it here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think, can everybody see the diagram, or should I render it in, mermint.com?
Krish NAik: let me know that. Because, here you have the actual GPT-40 vision, where we are cropping the bounding boxes, open it in browser.
Krish NAik: Alright, I can do it on browser front.
Krish NAik: Just hooked.
Krish NAik: Because this is where, actually, the cropping and everything happens, so this, flow is important, momentarily.
Krish NAik: My good.
Krish NAik: Why this is not getting collapsed.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. I think you guys can see right now, everything should be really good.
Krish NAik: For everyone, okay? So, now, these things, the starting 1, 2, 3, 4 blocks, you guys are already comfortable with, because this is the same thing that I have discussed in the first architecture. Focus on this one, when I'm talking about the enrichment of the chunks that we are doing for our multimodal, because text
Krish NAik: Really, I'm not worried about text. All I am putting my focus on image, tables, if I have formula, or if I have algorithms. Algorithms mean the pseudocode.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody understands the algorithms.
Krish NAik: Generally, if you, remember the CRAT paper, there you have the algorithms.
Krish NAik: Okay, so formula is different, and algorithm is different, don't get confused.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now here, the image modality, GPT4O Vision, here crop the BB box, because I'm getting the BB box cropping information.
Krish NAik: How we are cropping the mounting box information here, please tell me, in the chat.
Krish NAik: Arun is telling OCR, no, no, OCR is not doing. Layout detection is doing.
Krish NAik: In the layout detection, we get the output the BB box, the X1, Y1, X2, Y2.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Basically, it can be XYWH format also. Totally. I'm not talking about, like, pastel format or COCO formats, okay? Majorly, it'll turn in COCO formats only. XYWH, where you have the center point, you have the width and the height. If you have that particular information, you can simply crop it out.
Krish NAik: If you really don't know about bounding boxes,
Krish NAik: just go have a check on the bounding boxes, exactly, okay? Through bounding boxes, you can actually draw a rectangle. So that is actually the main…
Krish NAik: So, cropping the base, image 64, okay, and in PNG format, then, type captioning, okay, and then I'm doing a detailed structuring of that particular image.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this detailed structuring, you can actually get the information in imagecaptioning.py. When I will discuss the code waves, then I will let you know. Okay, but for now, this is where, actually, the cropping that happens when I look into the image modality only.
Krish NAik: Now, here, for tables, I don't need that one, because tables are not created as images.
Krish NAik: So here, GPT-40, JSON mod written type, the raw HTML that we get, and that HTML we rendered it in Markdown format, with a semantic summary. Now, this summary, if you have… you have to understand, you have the markdown table, so I can say my original table information is there.
Krish NAik: With that, a semantic summon.
Krish NAik: Now, you have to think, if this markdown table result is bad, then what will happen?
Krish NAik: What will happen, guys? Tell me.
Krish NAik: No, no, leave the semantic summary. I'm talking about the markdown table.
Krish NAik: Now, this is where, again, your retrieval quality will go down, what we were facing.
Krish NAik: Because I felt that in some of the cases, the table information… because if your semantic summary is already a summary, so we cannot expect from a summary to give us exact results. The exact results are being rendered from the markdown table that you exactly have.
Krish NAik: Now, rather than keeping the semantic summary, you can keep row-level information, or column-level information.
Krish NAik: For sure, the chunk size will increase. I can understand, but I can say that it will be much more detailed one.
Krish NAik: So, here also, that improvement can be done. It means that directly will say that, okay, generate each row information, or each column-wise information.
Krish NAik: And that also in whichever way, like, column-wise, row-wise, whichever works for you, according to the table structure that you can decide.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, retrieval quality will be down where? If the quality of the markdown, it gets, and finally, the semantic summary. And here, GPT-4, the JSON mode, JSON mode is coming from where?
Krish NAik: Because you already have the JSON data from your actual OCR, with layout analysis when you have done. So that JSON.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: That actual… the parsing results that you have.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this is where we are actually doing the enrichment. Always remember that. It means that the semantic summary, which we are adding, this is one level of enrichment.
Krish NAik: Similarly, for formulas, I have added the text, okay? Now, till now, in formula, I have not added the latex yet. I hope everybody understands latex.
Krish NAik: Because, how OCR model works, if you have a formula, it will render the latex in Markdown.
Krish NAik: Okay, but I'm actually not saving the latex in the chunk.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that nobody will ask a question like, what is the formula? If you have originally the formula, I felt that it is not required. If you feel that, if the end user might ask a question, then you need to save the latex also inside the chunk.
Krish NAik: Rather than I'm keeping the description of the formula. That's why verbal slash semantic description. I'm not keeping the latex.
Krish NAik: Is this part clear?
Krish NAik: Please let me know, everybody.
Krish NAik: Same thing we are doing for formula as well as algorithm. Text part is totally unchanged, because in text part, we maintain the structure much more, that this title is attached with this particular paragraph that comes.
Krish NAik: Please let me know. This is the enrichment part of the chunks, how we are enriching the image chunk, how we are enriching the table chunk, and how we are enriching the formula or the algorithm chunk.
Krish NAik: Because, see, enrichment means you already have the core information. On top of that, you are adding more information, so that your retrieval will be much more better.
Krish NAik: Alright, now from here, the final list of, entry chunks that I will be having, chunk.text, that is pretty much the direct information, chunk.caption, chunk.image underscore base64. This is the actual PNG. Okay, now this base64, later on, I can send it to anyone.
Krish NAik: It means I can send it to whom? The real Rankar backend, like Gina.
Krish NAik: Okay, they can actually look into the image, which can actually help them.
Krish NAik: Now, Mudassar is asking, here, the enrichment means we are adding the captions, right. We are adding the captions with, say, captions for images that we are doing. But in case of tables, we are adding a semantic summary. Similarly, for formulas, we are adding a semantic description.
Krish NAik: Captions can be only for images, okay, not for tables, because tables are not treated as images, neither formulas are treated as images, neither algorithms are treated as images.
Krish NAik: semantic summary, yes, you can keep it. But, see, generally, during the caption generation, I keep these type, like, detailed structure, like, I tell in the, prompt, basically, that, okay, you have to understand the flu understanding, and that we have kept a certain structure when I'm generating the caption for the images.
Krish NAik: Now, really, like, it totally depends upon the image, so you have to understand that the caption generation needs to be real, you have to look into the images, and then you have to decide. Yeah, for these type of images, these can be the conditions.
Krish NAik: Or it will be a pretty much big prompt if you really don't know exactly what is the image that will become.
Krish NAik: So, in those cases, I feel that
Krish NAik: Image embeddings, like, multimodal embeddings will be much more helpful, because this is where you have the bottleneck in your system, if you really go with text-based systems.
Krish NAik: And always remember the cost of multimodal embedding models are always 2x, as compared to 2. Just think about if you're spending only $20,000 on text, if you switch to multimodal, that $20,000 will become $40,000. So, always remember, vision-based solutions are 2x costlier as compared to text-based solutions.
Krish NAik: So always think that the budget constraint in your mind.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you're dealing with, image of Excel.
Krish NAik: an image of Excel table snapshots.
Krish NAik: then directly we can convert it into tables, Mitesh.
Krish NAik: If you have something, an image, I know that, yes, through an OCR and that. I really don't need to treat it as an image.
Krish NAik: If you take a text, just think about ABCD is written, you take an image of that, do you think that it is necessary to save that information? OCR can really do that, no? So, it is not required in that case, Mitesh.
Krish NAik: Product.
Krish NAik: Now, once I have done the chunk enrichment for the, I can say, modalities of image, table, formula, and algorithms, then the final chunk information that I have, and then I will move ahead with the embedding, and I will save it where
Krish NAik: in my vector database. Okay, so sparse vectors and dense vectors, okay, so similarly for the channels that we have, and then coming to our, main waste embeddings.
Krish NAik: Like, if I'm really going ahead with multimodal-based solutions, then again, the meaning of sparse vectors become really less. I feel that their,
Krish NAik: contribution to the final result becomes very, very less. Sparse vectors plays a crucial role in text-based solutions, not in multimodal-based solutions, okay? So if it is a text chunk, fine, but if it is really an image chunk, do you feel that it will have so much
Krish NAik: of contribution towards your result. Really, it doesn't, puts that.
Krish NAik: Okay, and finally, once you have your final one, this is the upstart operation, where you upload the chance, and then finally comes your quadrant part, where you save everything.
Krish NAik: Feature hashing. Feature hashing on top of what you want to do. Feature hashing on top of images you want to do.
Krish NAik: Generally, on top of Changs, we all… always add a very unique hash that we can add it. But specifically, feature hashing on top of what?
Krish NAik: That you want to.
Krish NAik: because here I have added it in sparse vectors, but again, if you really go away with multimodals, really, this doesn't matter. For our sparse vectors, I have kept it very specific, and this implementation of feature hash.
Krish NAik: It's directly from Quadrant that I have adopted it. Feature actually helps you to keep your sparse vector somehow towards lesser dimensions, okay? And this hashing
Krish NAik: actually helps you to make your search much more faster, based on certain type of criteria. It's pretty much like Movarva, if you know about Movarva-based algorithms. In those cases, hashing plays a very crucial role.
Krish NAik: And right now, Quadrant is also supporting Movearwa.
Krish NAik: So, really, for sparse vectors, it actually helps you, but again, I feel that not such a big contribution of feature housing with respect to sparse, that plays so much crucial.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this was all about the enrichment part that we have discussed. Okay, the main thing which was here was this part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just remember this part, how you can
Krish NAik: improve it, okay? The one part is, like, from this one.
Krish NAik: Changing the embedding models, that is one solution, but other than that, you have to focus on this particular structure definition. The bottleneck will be always here, if we go with this approach with text-based embedding models.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this part, you need to really work on.
Krish NAik: The more testing you have to do, a very thorough testing.
Krish NAik: Is this part clear for everyone? Can you move ahead with the next one? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Hmm?
Krish NAik: I think my Zoom window, alright?
Krish NAik: Alright, now this is a, back, let's go there.
Krish NAik: The text completion pipeline kind.
Krish NAik: The re-rank our backends also parsing pipeline, system.
Krish NAik: Now, I think, this is the… Retrieval pipeline.
Krish NAik: Okay, the retrieval pipeline, it's pretty much self-explanatory. As you have looked into the second one, that is the actual user query flow, what is attention. Embed.query, both the embedding needs to be generated, the sparse embedding as well as the tense embedding, then only it can make a query to your actual vector database.
Krish NAik: And right now, HNSW indexing support, I have kept it with quadrant. Okay, so HNSW actually helps you to make it much more scalable with respect to whenever you're working with any vector databases, everybody supports HNSW.
Krish NAik: Similarly, any other indexes that you know that you have worked with, except
Krish NAik: Ain and waste in Texas are there. Flat in Texting is there.
Krish NAik: Because, vector DB optimizations is a really separate topic, but, really scaling up vector databases. For example, if you want to do everything under 10 milliseconds, then what to do? If you want to really search on top of your entire, vector DB, then actually you have to move ahead with quantization-based solutions.
Krish NAik: Now, Abhijit's asking, how does test work in these architects? Is there any specific test design patterns that we need to follow?
Krish NAik: Generally, you have to create an evaluation set with GT by yourself. Till the time you don't have GT with you, nothing you can do it.
Krish NAik: Because at least you can ask the LLM to generate your JTs, but those JTs need to be validated by some domain expert.
Krish NAik: Alright, what's the time? It's 12, 9…
Krish NAik: You can go, I think, few others, because these are the easy ones, Melind, we will do it, okay? Because I feel that this is pretty much standardized things which are doing. Then comes your main RRF fusion, where you get the top K,
Krish NAik: Then, if you have any type of filters on top of your results, if it is said, if it is not set directly, like, then we can actually apply a quadrant filter on top of that.
Krish NAik: So that's why you had that filter modality that I have applied. And finally, once you have the final results, then it goes to the re-ranker backend, the four backends, whichever you have selected. Based on that, you will be getting your re-ranked spores.
Krish NAik: Okay, so re-rank yes or no, whichever condition. So, if it is yes, yes, the final, the top 10 results, and the list of chunks that we'll be getting. So, this is purely the retrieval pipeline. I don't feel this is anything new.
Krish NAik: Yeah, I'm good.
Krish NAik: So, after the retrieval pipeline, data structures limit data structures, how many of you know about the Pyrentic, models?
Krish NAik: Because this is pretty much the Pyntic models that we have. If you know the Pyntic models, the data models for Pyntic, exactly what is the input that is the structure that I have kept it. What will be the parse result? What will be the page result? What will be the chunk? So this is pretty much the Pyntic. If you look into the Pyntic files, then also you will get the same thing.
Krish NAik: Okay? So this is actually how the PyntonTech, data load looks like.
Krish NAik: Yes, graphite, I have not added.
Krish NAik: We can add anything, if… There is endless things.
Krish NAik: Right now, I focused only on the core multimodal part.
Krish NAik: Okay. Next class, we'll be making it much more multimodal if we change the embedding models.
Krish NAik: and a custom VLM support that we'll try to build.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes parsing pipeline, already we have discussed, but again, like, if you want. Because, see, I've added these diagrams, and these are pretty much self-explanatory.
Krish NAik: So spend some time. TDM, parser backend. First, like, if you're using the cloud in GLM OCR, you are not using the cloud, so we are going at with the Olama V.
Krish NAik: In Ulama, what you have, your main,
Krish NAik: OCR running, okay? And in, by default, ULAMA comes with PyPDF2. Look at this, PiPDM2 is the default package which comes with ULAMA. It means, internally, ULAMA uses it.
Krish NAik: So, directly, you can pass the PDF, and from there, we'll be getting the results, the element-based results. Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, from here, once I have the final JSON-based result with each indexes, okay? And always remember, with this Ullama support, you have also the detection layout also.
Krish NAik: Okay, it's not like only one thing is working, both the things are working parallel. First layout detection, then actually the OCR takes place.
Krish NAik: So, when you actually look into the code, first you will see that the layout detection model gets downloaded. And in the next step, the OCR widths that get downloaded. Okay, so finally, this is how the structure with respect to mounting box coordinates, you have your polygon coordinates also.
Krish NAik: Okay, you get your results in final markdown based on the final output type which you require it from the OLAMA backend running.
Krish NAik: And then, finally, from there, we'll be passing the results. Once I do have… these are the main elements, like label, content, bounding box 2D,
Krish NAik: Okay, polygon-based results, all those information that I have. Okay, and everything that I'll be assembling. So, why this assemble markdown? Now, this assemble Markdown doesn't come
Krish NAik: directly. I showed you that visualize operation. How many of you remember that I showed you that visualization? That for this PDF then, then actually this assemble markdown helped you.
Krish NAik: Because you need to get all the parsed elements, so that's why this assemble, markdown, through that, I can actually show the entire visualization and the generation of the markdown file. So if you have the parsed element, this JSON file directly, you can send it
Krish NAik: on top of your PDF to do any type of rendering. And finally, once you have those elements, you can get your final Markdown file. But this Markdown file will not have everything. It means that you cannot see the images, but the bounding box of those images will be there.
Krish NAik: Is this part clear for everyone? Because you have to always analyze the markdown files, so if you try to look, for example, in, docklinks, when I show you the docklink with dock layout.
Krish NAik: Okay, architecture, you were seeing the images. It means the actual base 64 was being rendered there, but in this case, we have not done the cropping yet.
Krish NAik: Till the time, if we have not done the cropping, we don't have the base64. If we don't have the base64, we cannot do the rendering directly in a markdown file.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes page results. Okay, and finally, whatever the results, this is your total number of animals, this is your raw markdown results that you get it, which you save it inside the output folder in our main workflow.
Krish NAik: Okay, then, I think chunking part, then in the next class, we will discuss. Let's keep it till, 1, 2, 3, 6, and we have already gone through the re-ranking backend. Other… you guys can have a look, but let's keep it till this point, too.
Krish NAik: Okay, because in the next class, it will be a little bit more practical, because I'll be… I won't be changing anything in the current
Krish NAik: codebase, I'll be creating a separate branch for the serverless-based architecture that we are going ahead.
Krish NAik: And, just let me know, like, in the next class, we'll be using a…
Krish NAik: When ranking model, when embedding model.
Krish NAik: Okay, do you want a Quen LLM also?
Krish NAik: and replace completely GPT or Gemini-based systems.
Krish NAik: Everything custom.
Krish NAik: Because just be sure, it's something, like, you need more amount of VRAM, that is the main requirement.
Krish NAik: So, like, I will try to make that at least let's host the LLM, because LLM will take a lot of VRAM. So, what I will do, I think the new models that came, the recent one, the Twin 3.5 family, the 20 billion model, the 27 billion model, that is really, really good.
Krish NAik: Okay, and… or I can pick up something like a… a distilled model, like, through knowledge distillation, which has been built on top of Opus. Yesterday, I showed you one model, the Quain 3.5, if you remember. It's through knowledge distillation, which has been built.
Krish NAik: Okay, so because the selection of the models really, like, when I try to decide, even I get, but, twin.
Krish NAik: Can you save this one?
Krish NAik: This is, again, this is through knowledge distillation, which the model has been with, and this is also a good one.
Krish NAik: If you really think about it, it has the revenge support also, and the quality of the model output is really, really good. So, something like a custom twin model, then also, I will replace GPT. Just remember, little bit, the response time will be high, but other things will be really working good.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, then in the next class, entirely we'll move to the Quen family.
Krish NAik: Okay, and just be sure everything, I want to be hosting it in local. Few things, I'll be keeping it through APIs, like through RunBot, I'll be executing at least the LLM, because LLM really… if I start… LLM takes a lot of VRAM. Directly, I know that 50GB of VRAM will be used, so it's better to host it in a separate environment.
Krish NAik: Rather than mixing it in our current solution.
Krish NAik: Completely open source tag. Alright, fine. The twin family stack, then, in the next…
Krish NAik: week, I will add it completely.
Krish NAik: I'll create a new branch, when branch, okay, and in that, I will just update everything with respect to it.
Krish NAik: I think it will be quoted that way. The poor application, we won't be hampering.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, see, by this time, at least you have the current code base, please check with the other 3Dancer backend that you have.
Krish NAik: Please at least explore by yourself, because now this is a point you have to do self-exploration.
Krish NAik: Multimodal is all about self. The more that you do research from your site, the more that you play with different re-ranker backends, multimodals, okay, and then multimodal embeddings.
Krish NAik: then you will really understand that, where it fails. Because really, I will say that twin models are really, really good.
Krish NAik: I feel that. I have used it in some open source solutions I have suggested. I felt that they are much better than OpenAI.
Krish NAik: That's why, like, the quality is really high. That's why in MTB leaderboard. But Gemini is better. Like, I feel that OpenAI is always toward the lower side, whereas Gemini is really, really good. That's why, in top 10 places, Gemini always
Krish NAik: earlier.
Krish NAik: Alright, so next week, we'll be creating an entire
Krish NAik: stack, and just be sure whoever is doing that in the input at least keep, $5 credit. We'll be spending around $1 or $2, but, do it, because for LLM hosting, I need that. Otherwise, I don't have any other options.
Krish NAik: Okay, so few architectures, rest of the discussion will be, so I feel that it will take…
Krish NAik: More 2 weeks to do the completion of the entire thing, as we are doing more work on the core stack.
Krish NAik: But it's fine.
Krish NAik: If you have not explored such things, it will be a good learning, really.
Krish NAik: Alrighty, guys, so I think you guys can start with some questions.
Krish NAik: And I'm good to take. So, any other suggestions from your side in the architectures that I can do it? Let me know, because I can add more and more things, but just remember, the more the complexity it arrives, because the retrieval time, we can make it very, very long.
Krish NAik: Like, query transformations, ID, everything we can add. But always, it comes with a cost.
Krish NAik: Do we have extra class next week? I think from next month, I was planning, but let's complete this project. Once we complete this project, then I'll be taking the extra class.
Krish NAik: Because those will be small, small topics. Page index, metadata enrichment.
Krish NAik: Okay, so those type of things. So, first of all, we will create a list, and then, because your final project, it is completed from my site, the Agenticarag one. It is based on Langraph. A lot of new things that you will be exploring.
Krish NAik: Rackflow is good, really. If you don't want to go into the internals of anything, so on. Rackflow, really good. I have really… a lot of developers gave me a good review on Rackflow.
Krish NAik: If you don't want to do anything from scratch, blindly go with RackPro.
Krish NAik: And really, as a developer, it becomes much easier. So, pretty much plug-and-play stuffs are there in Write me.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, guys, any questions, you can simply raise your hand, anything in the improvement of the application, because right now, we are in a stage where you have to pass your inputs. It's not like that everything. The more you do the research, then you can let me know. Those things, again, we can do the implementation.
Krish NAik: Rajat has registered, and yes, Rajat.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, hi, Paul. So one question I have related to the project and all… so, like, in the professional environment in companies, so these kind of projects are majorly done, or… on an average, I'm asking not a particular scenario.
Krish NAik: a project means, see, not programming…
Rajat Khanna: which includes, this, like, images detection, like, multimodal rack that we are doing. So, which includes…
Krish NAik: Otherwise, there is text, image, Tables, these are common things, I see.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everywhere, these type of documents you will be working around. I cannot say exactly the same, but yes.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, yeah. So, how they are managing their hardware resources? Because there will be, like, multiple developers working…
Krish NAik: access to cloud, no? In cloud, they are accessing directly GPU-based instances, as in AWS, you have, like, G6 class, so there you'll be getting the GPUs directly.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: But they won't be getting those type of things, like serverless GPUs.
Krish NAik: Because in Cloud, they don't have that.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Rajat Khanna: And, the other question is, regarding this, that cloud code that we install locally. So, how reliable, that is, like, to have a helping agent
Rajat Khanna: Or, like, if.
Krish NAik: For organization level or for personnel?
Rajat Khanna: for both.
Krish NAik: In organizations, generally, I don't think anybody will do that. See, I don't have any issues till the time you change the main API of Cloud. That is the first thing. It means that, see, if you're working in an organization, your organization will be specialized that these are the LLMs. Your company data wire will be sharing with Cloud.
Krish NAik: Okay, that is totally unethical. You don't need to share anything. What you will do, share your custom model for your enterprise, which is being hosted.
Krish NAik: Okay, that particular endpoint that needs to be changed, whether you are working with OpenPort, or… so, whatever is the port and whatever is the, that particular URL you will be getting from the organization, only these models that you are using. In that way, you have to do the configuration of plot code.
Rajat Khanna: No, no, like, like, in Copilot, so the companies are providing Copilot AI Agent Assistant. So, same as in, like, in Cloud Code, they might be… have a paid version, there will be… you can share internal…
Krish NAik: Now, their models, it's very specific to every organization if they are putting Copilot. Now, the co-pilot model configuration, it totally depends. Are they using custom ones, or directly they are sharing the data with the main, service provider?
Krish NAik: I don't think they are sharing the data with the service provider.
Krish NAik: Because then the… exactly a lot of things will be pretty much exposed.
Krish NAik: Pretty much unethical items.
Krish NAik: Everybody's configuring their own endpoints.
Krish NAik: Whenever you are working with any type of, like, coding agent, okay, so you have to remember that your model, that endpoint, you have to get it. You can ask someone from the team who will share it, or somewhere they will tell that you can actually hit the send.
Krish NAik: Because those custom endpoints are actually for your organization, that they use it, internally. Otherwise, your entire data will be going to cloud.
Rajat Khanna: And for personal use, it's advisable.
Krish NAik: For personal use, then expose it, then it doesn't matter.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because personally, who will host an LLM?
Krish NAik: Nobody does it.
Rajat Khanna: And, like, in the project, that current project, we are doing, so we have, like, in previous classes, we have different strategies, like, from re-ranking to hypothetical response generation.
Rajat Khanna: to RSF, RF, and changing the model, and all those things. So, like, the more things we will be applying to our system, the more latency it will be, and the.
Krish NAik: fortune.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, and more, cost… coasting of the system, that will be.
Krish NAik: Costing will also increase, but rather than costing, I'm much more worried about the latency part.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, generally, in document ingestion pipelines, it's fine.
Krish NAik: Like, if somebody… if you're not building such a system, if you feel that, okay, you are running it in batch, just like a cron job, every, like, one week, two weeks, or every day at a certain time, then it is fine. The document ingestion pipeline is going ahead.
Krish NAik: Okay, but the query one, where you are actually doing the retrieval, there you should have lesser latency.
Krish NAik: So, you have to pick up those things only which is working. So, it's not about putting everything together, rather than the… just look into, do the research, explore, and then pick up the components which you feel.
Krish NAik: Because if you feel that you are adding this component, and that component is only adding 30 milliseconds, it is fine. I can add. But if you are picking up a component which is adding 200, 300 milliseconds, then I will actually decide that, okay, really it is important in that way. Do the evaluation for this.
Rajat Khanna: And also, like, these systems, like, we have implemented in Lightning AI, so individual server is handling one person's requests and responses.
Rajat Khanna: So if there are hundreds and thousands of, that users will be there, so then, by default, the latency will increase if we are not changing anything. Like, for a single user, it might be latent.
Krish NAik: In that case, will you be launching, like, multiple instances?
Krish NAik: Then, the architecture is different. Then, like, from ECS Farget, if you are telling multiple instances, similarly, in Kubernetes, multiple ports will be launched. So, the same thing happens. So, there, like, horizontal scaling or vertical scaling totally depends upon the architecture that you are going at.
Krish NAik: More request comes, like, more requests means exactly what is. If you are feeling that if you are having something more than one lakh parallel request, in that case, better to go with Kubernetes. Otherwise, I think Kubernetes is always a costlier solution. If you're hosting, it's good, rather than using somebody's. EKS, AKS, everything, very, very costly, I think.
Krish NAik: But yes, if the enterprise is fine, they are going ahead, it's completely cool. Otherwise, most of the times, I feel that everybody fools their own Kubernetes info.
Krish NAik: then it's, like, 90x cheaper in long term.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, and overall, in the industry standards, so how, like, you see, like, this AI, gen AI, or these AI applications are moving towards more into automation, or more into application, development? Because I see, like, mostly.
Rajat Khanna: they are applying as automation, because they have their own current applications systems, that are there, and they are just integrating AI as an automation, not into individual application building, like in older softwares, like Chrome, Full Stack, front-end, back-end rules were there. So it was majorly into new application development, but currently, these AI-related solutions are for
Rajat Khanna: More into automation, not into individual application development.
Krish NAik: Now, see, it can be on both, it's not really. Automations are fine, because certain things are there through agents that you do the automation. But in certain things, you need to integrate the
Krish NAik: for example, like, any solution that you have built probably 8 to 10 years ago, the performance of that solution for certain things that needs to be upgraded, the recent ones, that I feel.
Krish NAik: Because the performance, if you really check, and if you really get that more than 20 to 30% performance increase that you can get, people are actually integrating the current, because that is where the actual research come on. Automation is lesser research. It's pretty much the agentic stuff that happens around.
Krish NAik: But actually, looking into the CV-based implementations, people are actually moving, like, how to move from CNN-based implementation to transformer-based implementation. They're actually… it's completely… they're changing the solutions.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, like, majorly, like, I have connected a few of my friends and all, so what they are, referring to, like, most of the companies are doing, they have their legacy code, or the old, code, which mostly in the organizations, they do migration from the old technology to new technology. And now, while they are migrating, they are just integrating few of the AI-related solutions into that.
Rajat Khanna: which might be speeding up the process, or just to have more exposure to the higher, hierarchical managers and all. So, like, we have included AI in this and AI in that, but majorly, like, they are just adding chat-based support, or just, doing…
Rajat Khanna: Like, faster implementation of the response generation and all.
Krish NAik: Previously, if the solution was not having AI, so really, I don't think anybody will integrate AI directly on that. But if there was already AI being implemented, now that AI is being approved. That's what I'm telling you. If there was no AI only, then why people will bring AI?
Krish NAik: Rather than in some things with respect to automations, report generation, those things, they can simply do it. That I can understand. But if there was no AI used.
Krish NAik: Pretty much logical stuff.
Rajat Khanna: No, like, normal chat application, they are referring to AI. Like, we do, like, a document we are uploading, and then based on those documents, we are asking questions. So, like, a normal chat application, they are being referring to as AI integration in the application.
Krish NAik: Alright, that… both the approaches are being done, but it's totally different. Like, if somebody's building based on codebases, for example, if somebody's building a chatbot based on legacy codebases, then at least I know that you need a system for that, so their rack will come into the picture.
Krish NAik: Similarly, you have to decide exactly what is the solution. I feel that AI integrations, yes, but rather than upgrading older AI solutions to newer-based stack, you're also doing it on.
Krish NAik: Because there is a lot of, I can say solutions which are based on LL, RNA and Celestium, they are being upgraded to transformer-based.
Krish NAik: solutions through SLMs. Everybody is building their own distilled, SLMs, okay, and they are actually using it. Because the inference time is also lower, because if you really try to compare them, for sure, LSM will be faster, but the accuracy is very, very high. We try to compare.
Krish NAik: So, in that week…
Krish NAik: they are applying. On top of knowledge distillation, they are bringing SLMs into the system. Okay, where they feel that SLMs are much harder than RAM-based systems that they are trying to…
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, and I have a few questions. I will not ask it here, like, for the newer badge and advanced rag and…
Rajat Khanna: So, just for debris.
Krish NAik: Do you ever match, like,
Krish NAik: Newer batch, syllabus next week I'll be sharing.
Krish NAik: Okay, by that time, 100%, it will be ready. But again, like, I'll be showing entirely what I have created, what exactly the final version, what will be drafted, I'm not sure, but I have added all the major topics till 2026 research, what has been done.
Rajat Khanna: And it will be taught by you, or some… another…
Krish NAik: only I will only be.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: The content is totally different from other batches, but yes, you can think about 30% relies there, if you check with the recent patch of Genite at Gottliemage. Similarly, the agent batch, if you look into the content, but I have taken a lot of inspiration from much more research. Like, if you're… the things, I feel that more than 80% of you might need.
Krish NAik: When you look. So it's something like that.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, next. Thank you, thank you, Juan.
Krish NAik: No, great. Any other questions anyone simply can ask me.
Krish NAik: I'll be concluding. So, before concluding, again, the codebase that I have shared, please do check it out. I think you already have your credits in Lightning AI. At least check the different backends in your local.
Krish NAik: If you feel that, try to play with things. It means that I have been using GLM OCR, try to replace it with battery OCR. So, till the time, if you are not spending, actually, then…
Krish NAik: It becomes, because directly, it cannot be a spoonful, like, spoon-feeding operation that I can do from my end. You have to spend, because multimodal solutions are much harder, because here, exactly, during inference's time.
Krish NAik: a lot of thing changes, because, that's… because OCR rates, you have to think about, none of the OCRs in the market is 100% accurate.
Krish NAik: On top of any benchmarking data set. Everybody is around 94%. So, 6% error rate, you always have to take it in your mind.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is what research shows.
Krish NAik: So, when you take a layout detection with OCR, we do have that. Similarly for cold paddy-based also.
Krish NAik: Nobody, in none of the places, we have 100% attributes. Always, like, you have to do the testing, and then only you can come up with a final, solution.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think I am good to conclude today. Okay, so next week, rest of the memory workflows we'll be discussing.
Krish NAik: then the quin stack, that I'll be creating it in a separate branch in the same codebase, that particular setup that I will be doing.
Krish NAik: And then finally, I think deployment will be next to next week. Then, next week, I'll be talking about the codebase. So, once the architecture discussion is done, then the codebase, and then finally coming to the deployment. I think it will be next to next week.
Krish NAik: Because in two classes, it's not possible.
Krish NAik: So, roughly around, you can take till the…
Krish NAik: Second week of April, we'll be completing this multimodal project.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so I'm now ending the session, so thanks everyone for joining. If you have any questions, drop me a mail.
Krish NAik: Okay, and with respect to the other projects also that you guys are doing in AWS and Azure, if you guys want to keep a meeting with me, just drop me a meeting.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in the weekdays, simply I can plan for it.
Krish NAik: Bye-bye, everyone. Thanks for joining.
Krish NAik: Murthosa is asking, will TextExtract or Azure Document better? See, that's, again, it totally depends upon the type of documents, because in TextExtract, Azure Document Intelligence, they have, like, custom models which have been trained on scan documents, GLM,
Krish NAik: But, really, like, I don't… don't have the benchmark for those solutions.
Krish NAik: You have to understand, if I don't have the benchmarks, then how I can do the comparison?
Krish NAik: Okay. I know that ESJ works. Like, Mestral OCR,
Krish NAik: I showed you Mestral Enterprise OCR, it worked, but in… I feel that in 2-3% of the cases, even Mestral Enterprise OCR also fails.
Krish NAik: Alright, so where you have… one simple example, let's take when you have overlapping of images.
Krish NAik: One of the most classic computer vision problems. When you have three different objects overlapping on top of each other.
Krish NAik: There, you will be having the problem.
Krish NAik: This is a classic example.
Krish NAik: Yes, like, that's why I'm telling you, some models are good on handwritten.
Krish NAik: Like, I feel that in the cloud till now, Azure Dop Intelligence is the best, what I have said, as even compared to TechStrat or Google Vision API.
Krish NAik: talk intelligence, till now I feel that, because the product has been good for a very, very long time.
Krish NAik: before, it was form recognizer, okay, so many times the name of the product that was changed, but in cloud, even, like, better than… do Mestrel claims, but I feel that,
Krish NAik: With respect to complex documents, what I have done the testing, doc intelligence is the best.
Krish NAik: If you're ready aspirin
Krish NAik: But, with respect to open source-based solutions, then I would say the Twin family, the other OCRs that came recently in 2026, in the past two months, really, everyone is working today.
Krish NAik: like Chandra OCR, okay. In the next class, you guys can bring at least one or two sample documents from your own site, which you feel that it is not working. Because I want your input, you feel that, okay, now this is not working for me.
Krish NAik: Bringing a document, we'll be doing the testing, like, right? In today's class, Saurabh shared one of his jobs.
Krish NAik: Okay, because once you feel that this is tough for me, let's try to work on that type of data, and let's see how we can improve the systems much better.
Krish NAik: test handling, anybody can do it, but really, multimodal handling, like, little bit more time. I will try to add Chandra OCR in the project, alright? Chandra OCR, so two suggestions, Chandra OCR or the Red Note one. These two, you can explore it, whichever you feel that gives any integration can be done in theory.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so I think, I'll be concluding it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so next class.
Krish NAik: the Quinn family setup.
Krish NAik: and code discussions with architecture discussions. And finally, next to next week, then we will start our deployment with, AWS Farget.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that will be… I think I have a few docs in the deployment, branch. In the meantime, if you want, you can… it's not finalized, but, a high-level idea that you will get exactly what we'll be doing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so bye-bye.